<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/index.html</id>
    <title>anari: slimfeed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-24T12:21:59.437Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.8.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How is COVID Changing the Geography of Entrepreneurship? Evidence from the Startup Cartography Project -- by Catherine E. Fazio, Jorge Guzman, Yupeng Liu, Scott Stern]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28787#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28787#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.562Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leveraging data from eight U.S. states from the Startup Cartography Project, this paper provides new insight into the changing nature and geography of entrepreneurship in the wake of the COVID pandemic. Consistent with other data sources, following an initial decline, the overall level of state-level business registrations not only rebounds but increases across all eight states.  We focus here on the significant heterogeneity in this dynamic pattern of new firm formation across and within states.  Specifically, there are significant differences in the dynamics of new business registrants across neighborhoods in terms of race and socioeconomic status. Areas including a higher proportion of Black residents, and more specifically higher median income Black neighborhoods, are associated with higher growth in startup formation rates between 2019 and 2020.  Moreover, these dynamics are reflected in the passage of the major Federal relief packages.  Even though legislation such as the CARES Act did not directly support new business formation, the passage and implementation of relief packages was followed by a relative increase in start-up formation rates, particularly in neighborhoods with higher median incomes and a higher proportion of Black residents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heterogeneous Global Booms and Busts -- by Maryam Farboodi, Péter Kondor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28834#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28834#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.473Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We investigate the heterogeneous boom and bust patterns across countries that emerge as a result of global shocks. Our analysis sheds light on the emergence of core and periphery countries, and the joint determination of the depth of recessions and tightness of credit markets across countries. The model implies that interest rates are similar across core and periphery countries in booms, with larger credit and output growth in periphery countries. However, a common global shock that leads to a credit crunch across the globe gives rise to a sharper spike in interest rates and a deeper recession in periphery countries, while a credit flight to the core alleviates the adverse consequences in these countries.  We explore the implication of the model about credit spreads, portfolio rebalancing, investment, non-performing debt and concentration of debt ownership during booms and busts, both in the time series and in the cross-section, and connect them to existing stylized facts. We further demonstrate how the anatomy of the global economy evolves as a result of aggregate demand and supply shocks to financing, such as a global saving glut.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Earnings Inequality and the Minimum Wage: Evidence from Brazil -- by Niklas Engbom, Christian Moser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28831#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28831#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.452Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We show that a rise in the minimum wage accounts for a large decline in earnings inequality in Brazil since 1994. To this end, we combine rich administrative and survey data with an equilibrium model of the Brazilian labor market. Our results imply that the minimum wage has far-reaching spillover effects on wages higher up in the distribution, accounting for one-third of the 25.9 log point fall in the variance of log earnings in Brazil since 1994. At the same time, the minimum wage’s effects on employment and output are muted by reallocation of workers toward more productive firms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deadly Discrimination: Implications of "Missing Girls" for Workplace Safety -- by Zhibo Tan, Shang-Jin Wei, Xiaobo Zhang]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28830#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28830#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.426Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We examine an indirect but potentially deadly consequence of the “missing girls” phenomenon. A shortage of brides causes many parents with sons of marriageable age to work harder and seek higher-paying but potentially dangerous jobs. In response, employers invest less in workplace safety, which in turn increases work-related mortality. Drawing from a broad range of data sets and taking advantage of large regional and temporal variations in sex ratios in China, we demonstrate that in areas with a more severe shortage of young women, the parents with unmarried sons suffer a significantly higher incidence of accidental injuries and workplace deaths.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research and Market Structure: Evidence from A Pathogenic Outbreak -- by Mayank Aggarwal, Anindya Chakrabarti, Chirantan Chatterjee, Matthew J. Higgins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28840#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28840#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.411Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do upstream research shocks directly and contemporaneously impact related but disconnected downstream product markets? We explore this question using a natural experiment involving the New Delhi Metallo-Beta-Lactamase 1 superbug pathogenic outbreak in India. Using a difference-in-differences strategy, we find that this upstream research shock caused multinational firms selling antibiotics in India to reduce their market exposure. Surprisingly, this void was filled by domestic Indian firms. These results are bolstered by a concurrent decline in multinational prescriptions of focal products by Indian physicians relative to prescriptions for domestic firm products. We present a stylized model building on a Cournot differentiated duopoly model to explain these heterogeneous responses. Results are robust to alternate control groups, including synthetic controls, as well as placebo testing. Implications for health policy and innovation policy are discussed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Resilient Is Mortgage Credit Supply?  Evidence from the COVID-19 Pandemic -- by Andreas Fuster, Aurel Hizmo, Lauren Lambie-Hanson, James Vickery, Paul S. Willen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28843#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28843#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.398Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study the evolution of US mortgage credit supply during the COVID-19 pandemic. Although the mortgage market experienced a historic boom in 2020, we show there was also a large and sustained increase in intermediation markups that limited the pass-through of low rates to borrowers. Markups typically rise during periods of peak demand, but this historical relationship explains only part of the large increase during the pandemic. We present evidence that pandemic-related labor market frictions and operational bottlenecks contributed to unusually inelastic credit supply, and that technology-based lenders, likely less constrained by these frictions, gained market share. Rising forbearance and default risk did not significantly affect rates on “plain vanilla” conforming mortgages, but it did lead to higher spreads on mortgages without government guarantees and loans to the riskiest borrowers. Mortgage-backed securities purchases by the Federal Reserve also supported the flow of credit in the conforming segment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Do Couples and Singles Save During Retirement? -- by Mariacristina De Nardi, Eric French, John Bailey Jones, Rory McGee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28828#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28828#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.385Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the savings of retired singles tend to fall with age, those of retired couples tend to rise. We estimate a rich model of retired singles and couples with bequest motives and uncertain longevity and medical expenses. Our estimates imply that while medical expenses are an important driver of the savings of middle-income singles, bequest motives matter for couples and high-income singles, and generate transfers  to non-spousal heirs whenever a household member dies. The interaction of medical expenses and bequest motives is a crucial determinant of savings for all retirees. Hence, to understand savings, it is important to model household structure, medical expenses, and bequest motives.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conglomerate Network -- by Kenneth R. Ahern, Lei Kong, Xinyan Yan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28837#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28837#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.318Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper proposes a network model of the economy in which conglomerate firms transmit idiosyncratic shocks from one industry to another. The strength of inter-industry connections is determined by the conglomerate's share of total industry sales and by the industry's share of the conglomerate's total sales. The empirical results show that industry growth rates comove more strongly within industry pairs that are more closely connected in the conglomerate network. These results hold after controlling for industry-pair and year fixed effects, input-output connections, reverse causality, and in tests that exploit exogenous cross-sectional industry shocks from import tariff changes. Finally, our model also provides a new cross-industry extension for the widely-used Herfindahl index of concentration.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Inflation Expectations of U.S. Firms: Evidence from a new survey -- by Bernardo Candia, Olivier Coibion, Yuriy Gorodnichenko]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28836#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28836#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.304Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing a new survey of U.S. firms’ inflation expectations, we document key stylized facts involving what U.S. firms know and expect about inflation and monetary policy. The resulting time series of firms’ inflation expectations displays unique dynamics, distinct from those of households and professional forecasters. By any typical definition of “anchored” expectations, the inflation expectations of U.S. managers appear far from anchored, much like those of households. And like households, U.S. managers are largely uninformed about recent aggregate inflation dynamics or monetary policy. These results complement existing evidence on firms’ inflation expectations from other countries and confirm that inattention to inflation and monetary policy is pervasive among U.S. firms as well.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributional Impacts of Retail Vaccine Availability -- by Judith A. Chevalier, Jason L. Schwartz, Yihua Su, Kevin R. Williams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28835#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28835#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.291Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As countries transition from facing COVID-19 vaccine supply shortfalls to requiring novel strategies to facilitate vaccination, modern retail chains—often designed and located to target particular demographic groups—are a potential vaccine delivery vehicle. Using geospatial data, we quantify the proximity to vaccines created by a U.S. federal program that distributes vaccines to commercial retail pharmacies. We then quantify the impact of a proposal to provide vaccines at Dollar General, a low-priced general merchandise retailer. We show that adding Dollar General to the federal program would substantially decrease the distance to vaccine sites for low-income and minority U.S. households.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning in the Household -- by John J. Conlon, Malavika Mani, Gautam Rao, Matthew W. Ridley, Frank Schilbach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28844#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28844#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.264Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study social learning between spouses using an experiment in Chennai, India. We vary whether individuals discover information themselves or must instead learn what their spouse discovered via a discussion. Women treat their 'own' and their husband's information the same. In sharp contrast, men's beliefs respond less than half as much to information that was discovered by their wife. This is not due to a lack of communication: husbands put less weight on their wife's signals even when perfectly informed of them. In a second experiment, when paired with mixed- and same-gender strangers, both men and women heavily discount their teammate's information relative to their own. We conclude that people have a tendency to underweight others' information relative to their own. The marital context creates a countervailing force for women, resulting in a gender difference in learning (only)  in the household.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorting Out the Real Effects of Credit Supply -- by Briana Chang, Matthieu Gomez, Harrison Hong]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28842#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28842#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.246Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We document that banks which cut lending more during the Great Recession were lending to riskier firms. To explain this  evidence, we build a competitive matching model of bank-firm relationships in which risky firms borrow from banks with low holding costs.  Based on default probabilities and equilibrium loan rates, we use our sorting model to recover  the latent bank holding cost distribution. The measure of banks with low holding costs dropped during the Great Recession. This credit supply shift conservatively accounted for around 50% of the decline in corporate loans over this period. Our attribution cannot be captured by panel regression estimates from the bank lending channel literature.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Welfare Analysis of Tax Structures with Love-of-Variety Preferences -- by Kory Kroft, Jean-William P. Laliberté, René Leal Vizcaíno, Matthew J. Notowidigdo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28838#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28838#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.233Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper reassesses the general trade-off between ad valorem and specific taxation using an economic model that features love-of-variety preferences and encompasses a wide range of market conduct – including both quantity and price competition – while allowing for firm entry and exit. We derive formulas for efficiency and incidence of both types of taxes that depend on the responsiveness of product variety to taxes and the effect of a change in product variety on consumer surplus. We use our formulas to derive a desirability condition for when ad valorem taxes are more efficient than specific taxes and a condition for when ad valorem taxes lead to greater pass-through than specific taxes. We identify and estimate the model parameters using a quasi-experimental ``county border pair'' research design that uses state-level and county-level variation in sales taxes combined with detailed scanner data covering grocery stores in the U.S. Our empirical results indicate that sales taxes are slightly overshifted onto consumer prices, have a large effect on quantity demanded, and have a more modest effect on the variety of products available to consumers. Using the estimated parameters, we recover consumers' love-of-variety, infer whether or not product variety is socially optimal (at current tax rates), and implement our desirability condition. We find that specific taxes are more efficient at the margin than ad valorem taxes given the estimated love-of-variety. This suggests that policymakers should consider using specific taxes and tariffs in markets with substantial product differentiation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contagious Unemployment -- by Niklas Engbom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28829#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28829#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.203Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent micro evidence of how workers search for jobs is shown to have critical implications for the macroeconomic propagation of labor market shocks. Unemployed workers send over 10 times as many job applications in a month as their employed peers, but are less than half as likely per application to make a move. I interpret these patterns as the unemployed applying for more jobs that they are less likely to be a good fit for. During periods of high unemployment, it consequently becomes harder for firms to assert who is a good fit for the job. By raising the cost of recruiting, a short-lived adverse shock has a persistent negative impact on the job finding rate. I provide evidence that firms spend more time on recruiting when unemployment is high, quantitatively consistent with the theory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dynamics and Spillovers of Management Interventions: Evidence from the Training Within Industry Program -- by Nicola Bianchi, Michela Giorcelli]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28833#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28833#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.189Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper examines the long-term and spillover effects of management interventions on firm performance. Under the Training Within Industry (TWI) program, the U.S. government provided management training to firms involved in war production between 1940 and 1945. Using a newly collected panel dataset on all 11,575 U.S. firms that applied to the program, we find that the TWI training had positive and long-lasting effects on firm performance and the adoption of beneficial managerial practices. Moreover, it generated complementarities among different types of training and had positive spillover effects on the supply chain of trained firms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agglomeration Economies and Race Specific Spillovers -- by Elizabeth Ananat, Shihe Fu, Stephen Ross]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28847#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28847#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.175Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Racial social isolation within and across workplaces may reduce firm productivity. We provide descriptive evidence that African-Americans feel socially isolated from Whites. To test whether isolation affects productivity, we estimate models of Total Factor Productivity for manufacturing firms allowing returns to local area concentrations of economic activity and human capital spillovers to vary with the racial and ethnic composition of both the establishment and the local area employment. Higher own-race exposure for establishment workers to workers at surrounding establishments strengthens the relationship between productivity and both employment density and concentrations of college educated workers. Effects for human capital spillovers are largest for firms with more patents and more research and development spending. Looming demographic changes suggest that this drag on productivity may increase over time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than an Ivory Tower: The Impact of Research Institutions on the Quantity and Quality of Entrepreneurship -- by Valentina Tartari, Scott Stern]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28846#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28846#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.148Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper provides systematic empirical evidence for the distinctive role of universities on local entrepreneurial ecosystems.  Assessing the impact of research institutions on entrepreneurship is challenging, given that these institutions are often located in economic and innovation environments conducive to growth-oriented entrepreneurial activity, are themselves a source of local demand, and produce knowledge, which might serve as the foundation for new ventures.  To overcome this inference challenge, we first combine comprehensive business registration records with a predictive analytics approach to measure both the quantity and quality-adjusted quantity of entrepreneurship at the zip-code level on an annual basis.  We then link each location to the presence or absence of research-oriented universities or national laboratories.  Finally, we exploit significant changes over time in Federal commitments to both universities and national laboratories.  Our key finding is that changes in Federal research commitments to universities are uniquely linked to positively correlated changes in the quality-adjusted quantity of entrepreneurship.  In contrast, increases in non-research funding to universities and funding to national laboratories is associated with either a neutral or negative impact on the quality-adjusted quantity of entrepreneurship.  Research funding to universities seems to play a unique role in promoting the acceleration of local entrepreneurial ecosystems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Entrepreneurs: Returns to Training Youth in Hard Versus Soft Business Skills -- by Laura Chioda, David Contreras-Loya, Paul Gertler, Dana Carney]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28845#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28845#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.135Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study the medium-term impacts of the Skills for Effective Entrepreneurship Development (SEED) program, an innovative in-residence 3-week mini-MBA program for high school students modeled after western business school curricula and adapted to the Ugandan context. The program featured two separate treatments: the hard-skills MBA features a mix of approximately 75% hard skills and 25% soft skills; the soft skills curriculum has the reverse mix. Using data on 4400 youth from a nationally representative sample in a 3-arm field experiment in Uganda, the 3.5 year follow-up demonstrated that training was effective in improving both hard and soft skills, but only soft skills were directly linked to improvements in self-efficacy, persuasion, and negotiation. The skill upgrade was rewarded in substantially higher earnings; 32.1% and 29.8% increases in earnings for those who attended hard- and soft-training, respectively, most of which, was generated through self-mployment. Furthermore, youth in both groups were more likely to start enterprises and more successful in ensuring their businesses' survival. The program led to significantly larger profits (24.2% and 27.2% for hard- and soft- treatment arms respectively) and larger business capital investments (38.4% and 32.6% for SEED hard and SEED soft, respectively). Both SEED curricula were very cost-effective; two months worth of the extra earnings caused by the training alone would exceed the cost of the program. These benefits abstract from the job- and business-creation benefits of the program, which were substantial: relative to the control group, SEED entrepreneurs created 985 additional jobs and 550 new businesses.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suburbanization in the United States 1970-2010 -- by Stephen J. Redding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28841#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28841#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.098Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second half of the twentieth century saw large-scale suburbanization in the United States, with the median share of residents who work in the same county where they live falling from 87 to 71 percent between 1970 and 2000. We introduce a new methodology for discriminating between the three leading explanations for this suburbanization (workplace attractiveness, residence attractiveness and bilateral commuting frictions). This methodology holds in the class of spatial models that are characterized by a structural gravity equation for commuting. We show that the increased openness of counties to commuting is mainly explained by reductions in bilateral commuting frictions, consistent with the expansion of the interstate highway network and the falling real cost of car ownership. We find that changes in workplace attractiveness and residence attractiveness are more important in explaining the observed shift in employment by workplace and employment by residence towards lower densities over time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opioid Use, Health and Crime: Insights from a Rapid Reduction in Heroin Supply -- by Timothy J. Moore, Kevin T. Schnepel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28848#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28848#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.081Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2001, a large and sustained supply shock halted a heroin epidemic in Australia. We use outpatient drug treatment records to identify individuals who accounted for nearly half of opioid overdoses prior to the shock, and examine how the reduced supply of heroin affected their health and criminal activity over the next eight years. Initially, the gains from fewer overdose deaths are offset by individuals substituting to other drugs and committing more violent crime, including homicides. Most adverse effects dissipate after one year, and are followed by further decreases in deaths and a large reduction in property crime. Our results demonstrate that reducing the supply of illicit opioids can lead to meaningful longer-term improvements, even when the short-term effects are ambiguous.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redesigning the Longitudinal Business Database -- by Melissa C. Chow, Teresa C. Fort, Christopher Goetz, Nathan Goldschlag, James Lawrence, Elisabeth Ruth Perlman, Martha Stinson, T. Kirk White]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28839#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28839#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.062Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper we describe the U.S. Census Bureau's redesign and production implementation of the Longitudinal Business Database (LBD) first introduced by Jarmin and Miranda (2002). The LBD is used to create the Business Dynamics Statistics (BDS), tabulations describing the entry, exit, expansion, and contraction of businesses. The new LBD and BDS also incorporate information formerly provided by the Statistics of U.S. Businesses program, which produced similar year-to-year measures of employment and establishment   flows. We describe in detail how the LBD is created from curation of the input administrative data, longitudinal matching, retiming of economic census-year births and deaths, creation of vintage consistent industry codes and noise factors, and the creation and cleaning of each year of LBD data. This documentation is intended to facilitate the proper use and understanding of the data by both researchers with approved projects accessing the LBD microdata and those using the BDS tabulations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Culture, Institutions and Social Equilibria: A Framework -- by Daron Acemoglu, James A. Robinson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28832#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28832#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.031Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper proposes a new framework for studying the interplay between culture and institutions. We follow the recent sociology literature and interpret culture as a \repertoire", which allows rich cultural responses to changes in the environment and shifts in political power. Specifically, we start with a culture set, which consists of attributes and the feasible connections between them. Combinations of attributes produce cultural configurations, which provide meaning, interpretation and justification for individual and group actions. Cultural figurations also legitimize and support different institutional arrangements. Culture matters as it shapes the set of feasible cultural figurations and via this channel institutions. Yet, changes in politics and institutions can cause a rewiring of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stock Market Spillovers via the Global Production Network: Transmission of U.S. Monetary Policy -- by Julian di Giovanni, Galina Hale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28827#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28827#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:17.015Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We quantify the role of global production linkages in explaining spillovers of  U.S. monetary policy shocks to stock returns across countries and sectors using a newly constructed dataset. Our estimation strategy is based on a standard open-economy production network model that delivers a spillover pattern consistent with a spatial autoregression (SAR) process. We  use the SAR model to decompose the overall impact of U.S. monetary policy on global stock returns into a direct and a  network effect. We find that nearly 70% of the total impact of  U.S. monetary policy shocks on  country-sector stock returns are due to the network effect of global production linkages. Our results are robust to changes in the definitions of stock returns and monetary policy shocks, to controlling for correlates of the global financial cycle, foreign monetary policy shocks, and to  alternative empirical specifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tax Evasion, Efficiency, and Bunching in the Presence of Enforcement Notches -- by Daniel M. Hungerman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28826#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28826#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.997Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent literature has studied bunching at notches in tax systems; but work on the implications of bunching for welfare has been limited. We consider a setting where there are discrete changes in the enforcement of tax compliance at certain levels of reported income, creating notches that can lead to bunching. We find that greater levels of bunching can be associated with greater tax efficiency. A simulation exercise demonstrates that notches with greater bunching can be associated with higher welfare than notches with less bunching, and that a tax system with  bunching at a notch can generate higher overall social welfare than a revenue-equivalent no-evasion linear tax.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Experiments with Children Inform Economics -- by John A. List, Ragan Petrie, Anya Samek]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28825#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28825#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.966Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the past several decades the experimental method has lent deep insights into economics.  One perhaps surprising area that has contributed is the experimental study of children, where advances as varied as the evolution of human behaviors that shape markets and institutions, to how early life influences shape later life outcomes, have been explored. We first develop a framework for economic preference measurement that provides a lens into how to interpret data from experiments with children. Next, we survey work that provides general empirical insights within our framework.  Finally, we provide 10 tips for pulling off experiments with children, including factors such as taking into account child competencies, causal identification, and logistical issues related to recruitment and implementation.  We envision the experimental study of children as a high growth research area in the coming decades as social scientists begin to more fully appreciate that children are active participants in markets who (might) respond predictably to economic incentives.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Long and a Short Leg Make For a Wobbly Equilibrium -- by Nicolae B. Gârleanu, Stavros Panageas, Geoffery X. Zheng]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28824#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28824#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.950Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We provide evidence that the online discussion on the WSB subreddit had a substantial negative impact on the profitability of shorting strategies across a number of stocks — even those that  were neither heavily discussed on the subreddit, nor experienced an unusual increase in retail buying volume. We provide a model to explain how fears among short sellers can become self-fulfilling. In the model, the market for shares and the lending market must clear jointly. Despite standard assumptions, the model features multiple equilibria and "run-type'' behavior by shorting agents.  More broadly, the model provides a tractable framework to interpret several empirical observations on the relation between short interest, lending fees, and expected returns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automated Enforcement of Irrigation Regulations and Social Pressure for Water Conservation -- by Jeremy D. West, Robert W. Fairlie, Bryan E. Pratt, Liam Rose]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28823#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28823#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.921Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This study evaluates two interventions for residential water conservation. Comparing households across an enforcement algorithm’s cutoff using a regression discontinuity design, we find that automated irrigation violation warnings cause substantial water conservation but also shift some consumption from regulated to unregulated hours within the week. In contrast, we show using data from a randomized experiment with the same customers that normative Home Water Reports reduce water use by a much smaller amount, but that this social pressure is effective during all hours both before and after automating irrigation policy enforcement. Our findings highlight the merits of implementing multidimensional conservation programs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Religious Festivals and Economic Development: Evidence from Catholic Saint Day Festivals in Mexico -- by Eduardo Montero, Dean Yang]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28821#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28821#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.907Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Societies worldwide spend substantial resources celebrating religious festivals. How do festivals influence economic and social outcomes? We study Catholic patron saint day festivals in Mexico, exploiting two features of the setting: (i) municipal festival dates vary across the calendar and were determined in the early history of towns after Spanish conquest, and (ii) there is considerable variation in the intra-annual timing of agricultural seasons. We compare municipalities with “agriculturally-coinciding” festivals (those that coincide with peak planting or harvest months) to other municipalities, examining differences in long-run economic development and social outcomes. Agriculturally-coinciding festivals have negative effects on household income and other development outcomes. They also lead to lower agricultural productivity and higher share of the labor force in agriculture, consistent with agriculturally-coinciding festivals inhibiting the structural transformation of the economy. Agriculturally-coinciding festivals also lead to higher religiosity and social capital, potentially explaining why such festivals persist in spite of their negative growth consequences.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Kinds of Distributed Generation Technologies Defer Network Expansions? Evidence from France -- by Nicolas Astier, Ram Rajagopal, Frank A. Wolak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28822#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28822#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.891Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper estimates the relationship between investments in five distributed generation technologies and hourly net injections to the distribution grid for over 2,000 substations in France between 2005 and 2018. We find that investments in distributed wind and solar capacity have little or no impact on the annual peak of hourly net injections to the distribution grid, while investments in hydroelectric and thermal distributed generation significantly reduce it. An optimistic analysis of battery storage suggests that high levels of investments are required for distributed wind and solar investments to deliver similar reductions in the annual peak of hourly net injections.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender Differences in Job Search and the Earnings Gap: Evidence from Business Majors -- by Patricia Cortés, Jessica Pan, Laura Pilossoph, Basit Zafar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28820#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28820#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.857Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To understand gender differences in the job search process, we collect rich information on job offers and acceptances from past and current undergraduates of Boston University's Questrom School of Business. We document two novel empirical facts: (1) there is a clear gender difference in the timing of job offer acceptance, with women accepting jobs substantially earlier than men, and (2) the gender earnings gap in accepted offers narrows in favor of women over the course of the job search period. Using survey data on risk preferences and beliefs about expected future earnings, we present empirical evidence that the patterns in job search can be partly explained by the higher levels of risk aversion displayed by women and the higher levels of overoptimism (and slower belief updating) displayed by men. We develop a job search model that incorporates these gender differences in risk aversion and (over)optimism about prospective offers. Our counterfactual exercises show that simple policies such as eliminating ``exploding offers" by allowing students to hold onto offers for an additional month, or providing them with accurate information about the labor market, can reduce the gender gap significantly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long-Run Effects of Sports Club Vouchers for Primary School Children -- by Jan Marcus, Thomas Siedler, Nicolas R. Ziebarth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28819#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28819#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.841Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting in 2009, the German state of Saxony distributed sports club membership vouchers among all 33,000 third graders in the state. The policy’s objective was to encourage them to develop a long-term habit of exercising. In 2018, we carried out a large register-based survey among several cohorts in Saxony and two neighboring states. Our difference-indifferences estimations show that, even after a decade, awareness of the voucher program was significantly higher in the treatment group. We also find that youth received and redeemed the vouchers. However, we do not find significant short- or long-term effects on sports club membership, physical activity, overweightness, or motor skills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disbursing Emergency Relief through Utilities: Evidence from Ghana -- by Susanna B. Berkouwer, Pierre E. Biscaye, Steven L. Puller, Catherine Wolfram]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28818#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28818#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.823Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government transfer programs to distribute food, water, or electricity at low or no cost have been widespread during the COVID-19 global health crisis. How does program design affect the efficiency and distributional implications of these policies? And what design features determine their political popularity? We study these questions in the context of a program to distribute relief through the electric utility in Accra, Ghana, using data from 1,200 households surveyed during the COVID-19 crisis. We find that distributing relief through electricity transfers has significant advantages. It enables an immediate government response to the crisis because it leverages the existing financial infrastructure between the government utility and households. Moreover, theoretical efficiency concerns about in-kind transfers are mitigated because the transfers are inframarginal for most households and electricity credit can be stored, with many even preferring electricity transfers over cash. These advantages do not preclude delays in transfer receipt and the exclusion of some eligible households, and the program is regressive in both design and implementation. The households least likely to receive relief are those who use less electricity, pay a landlord or other intermediary for electricity, or share an electricity meter with other users – all common among low-income electricity consumers in urban settings. Finally, transfer receipt increases support for the governing party, but support for the program drops significantly if even a fraction of its costs are to be recovered through future electricity tariff increases. Concerns around disbursing relief through utility transfers in this context thus arise not from efficiency loss, but from regressivity, distributional challenges, and politicization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring Quality Effects in Equilibrium -- by Seth Richards-Shubik, Mark S. Roberts, Julie M. Donohue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28817#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28817#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.789Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unlike demand studies in other industries, models of provider demand in health care often must omit a price or any other factor that equilibrates the market. Estimates of the consumer response to quality may consequently be attenuated, if the limited capacity of individual providers prevents some consumers from obtaining higher quality. We propose a tractable method to address this problem by adding a congestion effect to standard discrete-choice models. We show analytically how this improves forecasts of the consumer response to quality. We then apply this method to the market for heart surgery, and find that the attenuation bias in estimated quality effects can be important empirically.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Property Rights and Urban Form -- by Simeon Djankov, Edward L. Glaeser, Valeria Perotti, Andrei Shleifer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28793#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28793#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T04:28:16.770Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do the different elements in the standard bundle of property rights, including those of possession and transfer, influence the shape of cities? This paper incorporates insecure property rights into a standard model of urban land prices and density, and makes predictions about investment in land and property, informality, and the efficiency of land use. Our empirical analysis links data on institutions for land titling and transfer with multiple urban outcomes, in 190 countries. The evidence is generally consistent with the model’s predictions, and more broadly with the Demsetz’s (1967) approach to property rights institutions. Indeed, we document world-wide improvements in the quality of institutions facilitating property transfer over time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jump-starting investment for a strong and even recovery]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/jump-starting-investment-strong-and-even-recovery</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/jump-starting-investment-strong-and-even-recovery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jump-starting investment after Covid-19 is a crucial challenge for the sustainability of the recovery. This column highlights that incentives to re-launch investment remain crucial. Viable and new firms need to have access to additional new financing as we emerge from the crisis. Debt finance cannot be the only option. Incentives for recapitalisation of companies and access to equity or equity-type finance become increasingly important. The legacies of the pandemic in the financial sector need to be worked out quickly. European and government support complementing post-pandemic bank and capital market financing will be critical to a strong and sustained recovery.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Debora  Revoltella, Rolf Strauch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gendered laws do matter]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/gendered-laws-do-matter</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/gendered-laws-do-matter"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite the significant barriers to economic inclusion that many women face, there is a long history of scepticism regarding the relevance of laws that discriminate on the basis of gender. This column analyses global data on legal gender equality and shows that greater legal equality between men and women is associated with a narrower gender gap in opportunities and outcomes, fewer female workers in positions of vulnerable employment, and greater political representation for women. Country attributes that are significant predictors of legal gender equality (including religion, legal origin, and geography) evolve slowly, if at all. Nonetheless, considerable progress in legal gender equality took place in some parts of the world over the past five decades.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simeon Djankov, Pinelopi Goldberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How monetary policy affects the distribution of income]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/how-monetary-policy-affects-distribution-income</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/how-monetary-policy-affects-distribution-income"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fully understanding the distributional consequences of monetary policy requires looking at its impact over the entire income distribution and not simply at summary inequality measures like the Gini coefficient. Using uncensored administrative income data for Sweden, this column shows that while a monetary policy loosening substantially affects incomes across the entire income distribution, it does so relatively more in the tails, providing a U-shaped response pattern. The effects in the bottom are primarily…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Niklas Amberg, Thomas Jansson, Mathias Klein, Anna Rogantini Picco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory and reconciliation: The dangers of common enemy narratives]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/memory-and-reconciliation-dangers-common-enemy-narratives</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/memory-and-reconciliation-dangers-common-enemy-narratives"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To secure peace in the aftermath of violent civil conflict requires working through legacies of difference, even hate. But narratives forged for the purpose of peacebuilding often present a distorted retelling of events. Using as its example the cultural impact of a film released decades after the end of the American Civil War, this column illustrates how a version of the past that promotes unity or agreement at the expense of truth may foster new divisions, hindering the reconciliation process over the lon…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena  Esposito, Tiziano Rotesi, Alessandro Saia, Mathias Thoenig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccines for developing countries: IGM Forum survey]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/vaccines-developing-countries-igm-forum-survey</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/vaccines-developing-countries-igm-forum-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is much debate about whether the patents on Covid-19 vaccines should be waived to allow low-income countries to produce doses for themselves. The IGM Forum at Chicago Booth invited its panels of leading European and US economists to express their views on this issue and the broader challenges of vaccinating the world. As this column reports, a strong majority (87% of the panellists) agrees that rather than waiving intellectual property protection, the rich countries should pay the pharmaceutical compa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Romesh Vaitilingam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How high local public debt and local public banks crowd out private investment]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/how-high-local-public-debt-and-local-public-banks-crowd-out-private-investment</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/how-high-local-public-debt-and-local-public-banks-crowd-out-private-investment"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Germany’s current account surplus and corporate savings have both been increasing in the last decade. This column shows that German private investment has been low because it has been crowded out by local public bank lending to municipalities. Banks' statutory public lending requirements and the debt brake have both played a role in this, exacerbating the contractionary effect of fiscal consolidation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mathias Hoffmann, Iryna Stewen, Michael Stiefel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nondisclosures and naive consumers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/disclosure-theory-private-information-naive-consumers</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/disclosure-theory-private-information-naive-consumers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disclosure theory says that businesses in competitive markets will reveal the quality of their products—good or bad. That often fails to happen because buyers aren’t skeptical enough, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Microeconomics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[부의 대전환 코인전쟁/박성준 외 지음/한즈미디어(한스미디어)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271966870</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271966870"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T07:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[부의 대전환 코인전쟁
박성준 외 지음 / 한즈미디어(한스미디어) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791160076134
정가: 17,000원 / 판매가: 15,300원 / 마일리지: 850원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




2018년 암호화폐 열풍이 전 세계를 휩쓸고 지나간 후 4년, 인류는 금융 역사를 바꾸는 거대한 패러다임의 변화를 목도하고 있다. 비트코인으로 대변되는 암호화폐 혹은 가상자산은 한순간의 버블로 사라질 듯 보였으나 이제 수천 년간 인류 문명을 지탱해 온 화폐의 역사와 부의 미래를 뒤바꾸고 있다. 더욱 발전한 블록체인 기술을 근간으로 기존의 화폐 시스템을 온전히 대체할 움직임을 보이고 있는 것이다.

투자의 관점에서도 수많은 개인투자자들이 투자처의 한 축으로 인정하고 있는 상황이다. 지금까지의 상식으로는 도저히 이해할 수도, 마땅히 준비하고 대응하기도 어려운 현실. 과연 부의 대전환은 이루어지는 것일까?…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[오준석의 플러터 생존 코딩/오준석 지음/한빛미디어]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271952704</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271952704"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T04:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[오준석의 플러터 생존 코딩
오준석 지음 / 한빛미디어 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791162244371
정가: 28,000원 / 판매가: 25,200원 / 마일리지: 111원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




플러터의 기본을 빠르게 익히고 앱을 직접 만들며 필요한 기능을 알아가는 '입문 + 활용서'로서 독자의 시간을 아껴준다. '다트 언어 + 플러터 + 안드로이드 스튜디오 + 앱 개발'을 한 권으로 전달하므로, 다트(Dart) 언어와 플러터(Flutter)를 몰라도 빠르게 배워 앱을 만들 수 있다. 추가로 개정판에서는  플러터 2의 변경점인 널 안전성(Null Safety)에 대해 설명한다

[1부 플러터에 입문하기]
	
0장 플러터 개발 환경 준비하기 
_ 0.1 앱 개발 방식 소개
_ 0.2 플러터 소개
_ 0.3 개발 환경 구성
_ 0.4 마치며

1장 생애 첫 모바일 앱 생성하기 
_ 1.1 프로젝트 생성
_ 1.2 안드로이드용 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[파이썬으로 살펴보는 아키텍처 패턴/해리 J.W. 퍼시벌 & 밥 그레고리 지음, 오현석 옮김/한빛미디어]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271944317</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271944317"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[파이썬으로 살펴보는 아키텍처 패턴
해리 J.W. 퍼시벌 & 밥 그레고리 지음, 오현석 옮김 / 한빛미디어 / 2021년 06월 / ISBN:9791162244319
정가: 32,000원 / 판매가: 28,800원 / 마일리지: 126원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




파이썬을 활용한 프로젝트의 규모가 커지면서 육각형/클린 아키텍처, 이벤트 기반 아키텍처, 도메인 주도 설계 등 고수준 디자인 패턴에 대한 관심이 높아지고 있다. 이 책은 검증된 예제와 아키텍처 디자인 패턴을 소개하며 애플리케이션의 복잡성, 의존성을 낮추고, 테스트 스위트에서 최선의 가치를 얻는 방법을 알려준다. 또한 자바나 C#보다 간단하고 우아한 파이썬 코드의 장점을 잘 살려 각 패턴을 설명한다.

CHAPTER 0 도입
0.1 설계가 왜 잘못되는가?
0.2 캡슐화와 추상화
0.3 계층화
0.4 의존성 역전 원칙
0.5 모든 비즈니스 로직을 위한 장소: 도메인 모델

[PART I 도…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Direction of Innovation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714093?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714093?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:09:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugo Hopenhayn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are socially responsible banks more resilient?]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/vox-talks/are-socially-responsible-banks-more-resilient</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/vox-talks/are-socially-responsible-banks-more-resilient"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ESG – Environmental, Social and Governance – measures of bank performance are getting a lot of attention from shareholders and policymakers. But might more investment in ESG make banks less resilient? Thomas Gehrig tells Tim Phillips what the first research on this topic reveals.
Read More here: CEPR Discussion Paper, DP15816 Social Responsibility and Bank Resiliency by Thomas Gehrig, Maria Chiara Iannino, Stephan Unger]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Gehrig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The distinctive character of policy-driven stock market jumps]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/distinctive-character-policy-driven-stock-market-jumps</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/distinctive-character-policy-driven-stock-market-jumps"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the stock market moves in a big way, journalists try to explain why. This column uses next-day newspaper accounts to characterise the drivers of more than 6,000 big daily moves (‘jumps’) across 16 national stock markets. Policy-driven jumps account for a greater share of upward than downward jumps in all countries. Jumps attributed to monetary policy foreshadow much lower levels of future stock market volatility than other jumps. In another striking pattern, US-related news drives one-third of national…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott  Baker, Nicholas Bloom, Steven Davis, Marco Sammon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Financing climate change: International agreements and lending]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/financing-climate-change-international-agreements-and-lending</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/financing-climate-change-international-agreements-and-lending"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Paris Agreement explicitly recognises the need to “make finance flows compatible with a pathway toward low greenhouse gas emissions and climate-resilient development”. This column looks at the impact of the agreement on bank lending and finds that following the agreement, European banks reallocated credit away from polluting firms. In the aftermath of President Trump’s 2017 announcement of a US withdrawal from the agreement, lending by European banks to polluting firms in the US decreased even further. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yener Altunbaş, David Marques-Ibanez, Alessio Reghezza, Costanza Rodriguez d'Acri, Martina Spaggiari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technological progress, the business model of local news, and the nationalisation of our politics]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/technological-progress-business-model-local-news-and-nationalisation-our-politics</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/technological-progress-business-model-local-news-and-nationalisation-our-politics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local journalism is disappearing in the US, with a quarter of all newspapers shut down in the past 15 years. Using the case of television expansion in the mid-20th century US, this column investigates how a more competitive national news market affects local news provision and, in turn, voting behaviour. After the entry of television, circulation for local newspapers and the total number of original local news stories published decreased. Because of television’s more national focus, this points to a strong …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles  Angelucci, Julia Cagé, Michael Sinkinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[더 나은 삶을 위한 경제학/로버트 스키델스키 지음, 장진영 옮김/안타레스]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271835163</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271835163"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T02:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[더 나은 삶을 위한 경제학
로버트 스키델스키 지음, 장진영 옮김 / 안타레스 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791196950187
정가: 18,000원 / 판매가: 16,200원 / 마일리지: 74원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




영국의 경제사학자이자 『존 메이너드 케인스』 전기 3부작으로 세계적 명성을 얻은 원로 경제 석학 로버트 스키델스키 교수의 최신 화제작. 2008년 글로벌 금융 위기 예측 실패 이후 별다른 진보를 보이지 못한 ‘주류 경제학(신고전주의 경제학)’의 문제점을 총체적으로 진단하고 처방을 모색한다. 모두 13개 장을 할애해 ‘방법론적 결함’에서 ‘학문적 불완전성’까지 치밀하게 살핀다. 비판의 강도가 높고 범위도 넓다.

이 책에서 스키델스키 교수는 작심하고 주류 경제학을 공격하지만, 그 의도는 경제학을 향한 깊은 믿음과 기대에 있다. 그가 보기에 경제학이야말로 인류에게 ‘더 나은 삶’을 열어줄 수 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[스프링 부트 실전 활용 마스터/그렉 턴키스트 지음, 오명운 옮김, 이일민 감수/책만]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271824446</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271824446"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T00:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[스프링 부트 실전 활용 마스터
그렉 턴키스트 지음, 오명운 옮김, 이일민 감수 / 책만 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791189909307
정가: 28,000원 / 판매가: 25,200원 / 마일리지: 114원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




간단한 장바구니 예제를 리액터(Reactor)를 활용한 논블로킹/비동기 방식으로 구현하며 비밀을 파헤쳐본다. 스프링 헤이티오스(HATEOS)를 적용해서 변경 여파를 최소화하면서 진화하는 API를 만들어보고, 스프링 레스트 독(REST Doc)을 사용해서 소스 코드와 일치하는 API 문서를 작성해본다. AMQP 메시징을 활용해서 느슨하게 연결된 이벤트 중심 아키텍처를 구현해보고, 양방향 리액티브 프로토콜인 R소켓을 사용해서 HTTP보다 효율적인 최신 네트워크 프로그래밍 기법도 익힌다.

[1장] 스프링 부트 웹 애플리케이션 만들기
스프링 부트란 무엇인가
리액티브 프로그래밍 소개
___리액터 타입
스프링 웹플럭스…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public debt and economic recovery]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/public-debt-and-economic-recovery</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/public-debt-and-economic-recovery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debt-financed fiscal expansions have been a critical feature in many countries’ policy response to Covid-19. This column revisits the role of public debt in stimulating economic recovery. The authors identify both short-run and long-run effects, highlighting that higher public debt has small effects on the capital stock but leads to a sizable decline of the liquidity premium, which increases the fiscal burden of debt. Further, the revenue-maximising level of public debt is positive and has increased to 60% …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Bayer, Benjamin Born, Ralph Luetticke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to improve tax compliance]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/how-improve-tax-compliance</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/how-improve-tax-compliance"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tax compliance lies at the heart of well-functioning societies, but the US and Europe lose vast sums annually to tax avoidance. This column discusses the results of population-wide experiments run in collaboration with the Belgium tax authority beginning in 2014. It finds that simplifying communication from tax administrators can improve tax compliance, nudge taxpayers to pay on time, and make late filers comply more swiftly. Communication – an inherent part of any tax administration – merits more attention…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan-Emmanuel De Neve, Clément Imbert, Johannes Spinnewijn, Teodora Tsankova, Maarten Luts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slowdown in business dynamics during the COVID pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/slowdown-business-dynamics-during-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/slowdown-business-dynamics-during-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The COVID-19 crisis may affect future productivity through its impact on business dynamics. This column argues that business dynamics – in particular business entries, exits, and bankruptcies – are slowing down, which can have adverse effects on long-term productivity. Over the course of 2020, fewer new businesses were established than in any ‘normal’ year and fewer closed down than during the Global Crisis in 2009. Most new entrants are self-employed and online businesses, especially in the wholesale and r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fozan  Fareed, Bastiaan Overvest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trickle down corruption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/corruption-test-cheating-mexico</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/corruption-test-cheating-mexico"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Political corruption isn’t just bad governance. It may also erode ethical standards in the rest of society, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Applied Economicsg.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss Aversion in Housing Sales Prices: Evidence from Focal Point Bias -- by Stephen L. Ross, Tingyu Zhou]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28796#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28796#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:52.414Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Estimates of loss aversion in housing sales prices may be biased because expected losses correlate with housing and borrower unobservables. We provide new evidence of loss aversion in sales price by differencing loss aversion estimates between sellers who exhibit focal point bias in their initial mortgage amount and those who do not. Although focal point bias and loss aversion are associated with different families of behaviors, recent evidence suggests links between these biases. Revisiting experimental da…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Human Capitalists -- by Andrea L. Eisfeldt, Antonio Falato, Mindy Z. Xiaolan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28815#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28815#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.475Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The widespread and growing use of equity-based compensation has transformed high-skilled labor from a pure labor input to a class of "human capitalists." We show that high-skilled labor earns substantial income in the form of equity claims to firms' future dividends and capital gains. Equity-based compensation has dramatically increased since the 1980s, representing forty percent of total compensation to high-skilled labor in recent years. Ignoring equity income causes incorrect measurement of the returns t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyclical Worker Flows: Cleansing vs. Sullying -- by John C. Haltiwanger, Henry R. Hyatt, Erika McEntarfer, Matthew Staiger]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28802#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28802#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.460Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do recessions speed up or impede productivity-enhancing reallocation? To investigate this question, we use U.S. linked employer-employee data to examine how worker flows contribute to productivity growth over the business cycle. We find that in expansions high-productivity firms grow faster primarily by hiring workers away from lower-productivity firms. The rate at which job-to-job flows move workers up the productivity ladder is highly procyclical. Productivity growth slows during recessions when this job …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Were Late-Nineteenth-Century, Small-Town Americans Life-Cycle Savers? -- by Howard Bodenhorn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28810#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28810#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.441Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although the mobilization of savings is an important function of banks and other financial institutions, there is remarkably little evidence that bears on how and how well the financial sector mobilized household savings in the nineteenth and early twentieth century. This paper documents financial wealth accumulated by working-class Americans to see whether their behaviors followed the predictions of the life-cycle hypothesis. Hand-coded data from an Upstate New York savings bank matched to federal and stat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Paid Family Leave in Labor Supply Responses to a Spouse’s Disability or Health Shock -- by Priyanka Anand, Laura Dague, Kathryn L. Wagner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28808#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28808#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.401Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The onset of a disability or major health shock can affect the labor supply of not only those experiencing the event but also their family members. Potential caregivers face a tradeoff between time spent earning income for the family and providing care for their spouse, which could be affected by the availability of paid leave. We examine caregiving and labor supply decisions after a spouse’s disability or health shock and the role of paid leave laws implemented in California and New Jersey in the response …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quantitative Framework for Analyzing the Distributional Effects of Incentive Schemes -- by Hugh Macartney, Robert McMillan, Uros Petronijevic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28816#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28816#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.384Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper develops the first quantitative framework for analyzing distributional effects of incentive schemes in public education. The analysis is built around a hump-shaped effort function, estimated semi-parametrically using exogenous incentive variation and rich administrative data. We identify key primitives that rationalize this effort function by estimating a flexible teacher effort-choice model. Both the model and parameter estimates are necessary components in our counterfactual framework for traci…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying Bias Correction for Selective Sampling: A Unified Distribution-Free Approach to Handling Endogenously Selected Samples -- by Yi Qian, Hui Xie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28801#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28801#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.365Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unlike random sampling, selective sampling draws units based on the outcome values, such as over-sampling rare events in choice outcomes and extreme activities on continuous and count outcomes. Despite high cost effectiveness for marketing research, such endogenously selected samples must be carefully analyzed to avoid selection bias. We introduce a unified and efficient approach based on semiparametric odds ratio (SOR) models applicable for categorical, continuous and count response data collected using se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immigrant Distribution in the United States during the Age of Mass Migration -- by Ariell Zimran]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28812#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28812#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.331Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immigrant distribution--the geographic dispersion of immigrants in the destination country--was a major issue in the United States in the late Age of Mass Migration. Policy debates were influenced by the widely held view that the new immigrants were generally less geographically mobile within the United States and specifically less likely to leave urban areas than were natives and earlier immigrants. I build new linked census datasets to investigate these claims by studying the rates of, selection into, and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI Adoption and System-Wide Change -- by Ajay K. Agrawal, Joshua S. Gans, Avi Goldfarb]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28811#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28811#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.316Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analyses of AI adoption focus on its adoption at the individual task level. What has received significantly less attention is how AI adoption is shaped by the fact that organisations are composed of many interacting tasks. AI adoption may, therefore, require system-wide change which is both a constraint and an opportunity. We provide the first formal analysis where multiple tasks may be part of a modular or non-modular system. We find that reliance on AI, a prediction tool, increases decision variation whic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Macroeconomic Effects of a Carbon Tax to Meet the U.S. Paris Agreement Target: The Role of Firm Creation and Technology Adoption -- by Alan Finkelstein Shapiro, Gilbert E. Metcalf]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28795#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28795#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.291Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We analyze the quantitative labor market and aggregate effects of a carbon tax in a framework with pollution externalities and equilibrium unemployment. Our model incorporates endogenous labor force participation and two margins of adjustment influenced by carbon taxes: (1) firm creation and (2) green production-technology adoption.  A carbon-tax policy that reduces carbon emissions by 35 percent – roughly the emissions reductions that will be required under the Biden Administration's new commitment under t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language Barriers in Multinationals and Knowledge Transfers -- by Louise Guillouet, Amit Khandelwal, Rocco Macchiavello, Matthieu Teachout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28807#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28807#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.276Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A distinct feature of MNCs is a three-tier organizational structure: foreign managers (FMs) supervise domestic managers (DMs) who supervise production workers. Language barriers between FMs and DMs could impede transfers of management knowledge. We develop a model in which DMs learn general management by communicating with FMs, but communication effort is non-contractible. These conditions generate sub-optimal communication within the MNC. If communication is complementary with language skills, the planner …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Man vs. Machine to Man + Machine: The Art and AI of Stock Analyses -- by Sean Cao, Wei Jiang, Junbo L. Wang, Baozhong Yang]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28800#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28800#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.262Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An AI analyst we build to digest corporate financial information, qualitative disclosure and macroeconomic indicators is able to beat the majority of human analysts in stock price forecasts and generate excess returns compared to following human analyst. In the contest of “man vs machine,” the relative advantage of the AI Analyst is stronger when the firm is complex, and when information is high-dimensional, transparent and voluminous. Human analysts remain competitive when critical information requires ins…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Can Developing Cities Today Learn From the Urban Past? -- by Edward L. Glaeser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28814#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28814#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.235Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The downsides of density, including traffic congestion, contagious disease and crime, were common in Victorian London and classical Rome, just as they are today in Sao Paulo and Lagos. Our urban past provides lessons for developing world cities today. The first lesson, that I highlight, is that political power, not commerce, has long driven the growth of the world’s largest cities, and that fact remains true for many developing world mega-cities today.  The second lesson is that while market access fundamen…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Public Equity Deadly? Evidence from Workplace Safety and Productivity Tradeoffs in the Coal Industry -- by Erik P. Gilje, Michael D. Wittry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28798#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28798#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.151Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study how ownership structure, in particular public listing status, affects workplace safety and productivity tradeoffs. Theory offers competing hypotheses on how listing related frictions affect these tradeoffs. We exploit detailed asset-level data in the U.S. coal industry and find that workplace safety deteriorates dramatically under public firm ownership, primarily in mines that experience the largest productivity increases. We find evidence consistent with information asymmetry between managers and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statewide Reopening During Mass Vaccination: Evidence on Mobility, Public Health and Economic Activity from Texas -- by Dhaval M. Dave, Joseph J. Sabia, Samuel Safford]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28804#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28804#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.137Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the first four months of 2021, the United States distributed approximately 250 million doses of COVID-19 vaccinations, which resulted in the complete vaccination of nearly 45 percent of the adult population.  In the midst of this mass vaccination effort, Texas became the first state to abolish its statewide mask mandate and fully lift capacity constraints for all businesses.  Governor Greg Abbott’s order was met with (i) concern by public health officials that an early reopening would lead to a resur…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Globalization and the Environment -- by Brian R. Copeland, Joseph S. Shapiro, M. Scott Taylor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28797#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28797#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:51.104Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How should international economic policy address climate change? Does trade cause deforestation and endangered species depletion? How does globalization affect air and water pollution? Do trade and investment create a race to the bottom in environmental policy? How important are environmental impacts of transporting goods? We review theory and empirical work linking international trade and the environment with a focus on recent work and methods.  We discuss the literature linking trade to local and global p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are High-Interest Loans Predatory? Theory and Evidence from Payday Lending -- by Hunt Allcott, Joshua J. Kim, Dmitry Taubinsky, Jonathan Zinman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28799#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28799#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.932Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is often argued that people might take on too much high-cost debt because they are present focused and/or overoptimistic about how soon they will repay. We measure borrowers' present focus and overoptimism using an experiment with a large payday lender. Although the most inexperienced quartile of borrowers underestimate their likelihood of future borrowing, the more experienced three quartiles predict correctly on average. This finding contrasts sharply with priors we elicited from 103 payday lending and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experiences and Coping Strategies of College Students During the COVID-19 Pandemic -- by Christine Logel, Philip Oreopoulos, Uros Petronijevic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28803#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28803#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.918Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An emerging literature documents the many challenges faced by college students during the COVID-19 pandemic. Little is known, however, about how students responded to the adversity. Focusing on two large Canadian universities, we provide some of the first evidence on the coping strategies students reported and the relationships between their endorsement of specific coping strategies and their subsequent well-being. Students focused on compensating for a lack of structure by creating new routines, maintainin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Household Debt Overhang Did Hardly Cause a Larger Spending Fall during the Financial Crisis in the UK -- by Lars E.O. Svensson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28806#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28806#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.890Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The “debt-overhang hypothesis” – that households cut back more on their spending in a crisis when they have higher levels of outstanding mortgage debt (Dynan, 2012) – seems to be taken for granted by macroprudential authorities in several countries in their policy decisions, as well as by the international organizations that evaluate and comment on countries’ macroprudential policy. Results are presented for UK microdata that reject the debt-overhang hypothesis. The results instead support the “spending-nor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Changing Relationship between Bodyweight and Longevity in High- and Low-Income Countries -- by Joanna Aleksandra Kopinska, Vincenzo Atella, Jay Bhattacharya, Grant Miller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28813#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28813#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.872Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Standard measures of bodyweight (overweight and obese, for example) fail to reflect technological progress over time - and in particular, recent progress disproportionately promoting longevity at higher bodyweights (and differences in access to it). This paper builds on the pioneering work of HansWaaler (Waaler, 1984) and Robert Fogel (Fogel, 1994) to empirically estimate how technological progress, and differential access to it, have fundamentally transformed the relationship between body mass index (BMI) …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Business of City Hall -- by Kenneth R. Ahern]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28805#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28805#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.852Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Compared to the federal government, the average citizen in the U.S. has far greater interaction with city governments, including policing, health services, zoning laws, utilities, schooling, and transportation.  At the regional level, it is city governments that provide the infrastructure and services that facilitate agglomeration economies in urban areas.  However, there is relatively little empirical evidence on the operations of city governments as economic entities.  To overcome deficiencies in traditio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cream Skimming by Health Care Providers and Inequality in Health Care Access: Evidence from a Randomized Field Experiment -- by Anna Werbeck, Ansgar  Wübker, Nicolas R. Ziebarth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28809#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28809#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.823Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using a randomized field experiment, we show that health care specialists cream-skim patients by their expected profitability. In the German two-tier system, outpatient reimbursement rates for both public and private insurance are centrally determined but are significantly higher for the privately insured. In our field experiment, following a standardized protocol, the same hypothetical patient called 991 private practices in 36 German counties to schedule appointments for allergy tests, hearing tests and g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Value of a Slender Spouse: Couples Agree that Keeping the Wife Svelte is more Valuable than Keeping the Husband Fit -- by Kristjana Baldursdottir, Paul McNamee, Edward C. Norton, Tinna Laufey Asgeirsdóttir]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28791#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28791#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.695Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to the World Health Organization, obesity is one of the greatest public-health challenges of the 21st century. Body weight is also known to affect individuals’ self-esteem and interpersonal relationships, including romantic ones. We estimate “utility-maximizing” Body Mass Index (BMI) and calculate the implied monetary value of changes in both individual and spousal BMI, using the compensating income variation method and data from the Swiss Household Panel. Two-stage least squares models are estima…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Endogenous Driving Behavior in Tests of Racial Profiling -- by Jesse Kalinowski, Matthew B. Ross, Stephen L. Ross]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28789#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28789#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.680Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[African-American motorists may adjust their driving in response to increased scrutiny by police. In daylight, when their race is more easily observable, minority motorists are the only group less likely to have fatal motor vehicle accidents. In Massachusetts and Tennessee, we find that African-Americans are the only group of stopped motorists with slower speeds in daylight. Consistent with an illustrative model, these speed shifts are concentrated at higher percentiles of the distribution. Calibration of th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Effects of Career and Technical Education: Evidence from the Connecticut Technical High School System -- by Eric Brunner, Shaun Dougherty, Stephen L. Ross]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28790#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28790#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.648Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We examine the effect of attending stand-alone technical high schools on student short- and long-term outcomes using a regression discontinuity design. Male students are 10 percentage points more likely to graduate from high school and have half a semester less time enrolled in college, although effects on college fade-out. Male students have 32% higher quarterly earnings. Earnings effects may in part reflect general skills: male students have higher attendance rates and test scores, and industry fixed effe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Legal Origins of Financial Development: Evidence from the Shanghai Concessions -- by Ross Levine, Chen Lin, Chicheng Ma, Yuchen Xu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28794#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28794#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:50.624Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We assemble new data on the British and French concessions in Shanghai between 1845 and 1936 to assess the legal origins view of financial development. During this period, two regime changes altered the degree to which the British common and French civil law traditions held jurisdiction over the respective concessions: the 1869 formation of the Mixed Courts strengthened Western legal jurisdiction, while the 1926 rendition agreement returned those courts to Chinese control. By examining the changing applicat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Aggregate and Distributional Effects of Spatial Frictions -- by Sebastian Heise, Tommaso Porzio]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28792#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28792#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:49.999Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We develop a general equilibrium model of frictional labor reallocation across firms and regions, and use it to quantify the aggregate and distributional effects of spatial frictions that hinder worker mobility across regions in Germany. The model leverages matched employer-employee data to unpack spatial frictions into different types while isolating them from labor market frictions that operate also within region. The estimated model shows sizable spatial frictions between East and West Germany, especiall…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merger or Acquisition? Introduction to the Handbook of Historical Economics -- by Alberto Bisin, Giovanni Federico]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28786#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28786#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:49.979Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The relationship between history and economics as academic disciplines is methodologically subtle and sociologically contested. If the Cliometric revolution can be characterized as an acquisition of economics by history, the most recent trends in Historical Economics appear to turn this relationship on its head. In this Introduction we read the chapters of the Handbook as a forceful argument in favor of a merger between the two disciplines rather than the acquisition of one by the other; a merger which comb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Cross-Section of Household Preferences -- by Laurent E. Calvet, John Y. Campbell, Francisco Gomes, Paolo Sodini]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nber.org/papers/w28788#fromrss</id>
        <link href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28788#fromrss"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T01:55:49.951Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper estimates the cross-sectional distribution of Epstein-Zin preference parameters in a large administrative panel of Swedish households. We consider life-cycle model of saving and portfolio choice that incorporates risky labor income, safe and risky financial assets inside and outside retirement accounts, and real estate. We study middle-aged stock-owning households grouped by education, industry of employment, and birth cohort as well as by their accumulated wealth and risky portfolio shares. We f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU fiscal policies in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/eu-fiscal-policies-2020</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/eu-fiscal-policies-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, EU member states launched massive fiscal measures to mitigate the economic and social fallout of the Covid pandemic. The activation of the severe economic downturn clause of the Stability and Growth Pact, coupled with a decisive intervention of the ECB, offered member states the flexibility to stage their fiscal response. As this column reveals, however, a closer look through the lens of an expenditure benchmark highlights important cross-country differences reflecting deeper issues. Countries with…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Larch, Janis Malzubris, Stefano Santacroce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The ghost of Smoot-Hawley tells why America isn’t too big to avoid retaliation]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/ghost-smoot-hawley-tells-why-america-isn-t-too-big-avoid-retaliation</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/ghost-smoot-hawley-tells-why-america-isn-t-too-big-avoid-retaliation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Trump administration’s pursuit of protectionist trade policies was predicated to some extent on the belief that America was too lucrative a market to face retaliation. Using the most detailed data set of bilateral trade flows constructed to date for the interwar period, this column shows that in fact the US faced substantial and widespread retaliation from trade partners in response to protectionist measures employed in the wake of the Great Depression. Exports to retaliating countries fell by as much a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kris Mitchener, Kevin O'Rourke, Kirsten Wandschneider</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[소프트뱅크 거액적자의 결말과 메가뱅크 위기/구로카와 아쓰히코 지음, 강철구 옮김/어문학사]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271715863</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271715863"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[소프트뱅크 거액적자의 결말과 메가뱅크 위기
구로카와 아쓰히코 지음, 강철구 옮김 / 어문학사 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788961849982
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 59원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




소프트뱅크와 메가뱅크를 중심으로 자본의 움직임에 주목한다. 최근 자본의 이동은 코로나 팬데믹으로 금융시장에 팽창을 일으키며 지금까지와는 전혀 다른 새로운 시대를 예견한다. 필자는 전 세계에 거품과 불황이 동시에 일어나는 코로나 쇼크를 우려하며 일본 경제를 진단하고 대책을 마련한다.

시작하며 ? 본격적인 금융위기의 경고

제1장 소프트뱅크 적자의 실상
원자폭탄급 대적자 
사라져 버린 수요 
차라리 파산시키는 게 어떨까 
피자 굽는 로봇회사의 예상 착오 
“나는 투자의 신이다” 
분명 “투자회사”이기는 한데...
쓰레기주 펀드 
상장폐지를 검토한 이유 
결국 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Bigger Banks Better? Firm-Level Evidence from Germany]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714120?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714120?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T02:21:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kilian Huber</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[부와 권력의 비밀, 지도력(地圖力)/김이재 지음/쌤앤파커스]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271700703</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271700703"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T02:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[부와 권력의 비밀, 지도력(地圖力)
김이재 지음 / 쌤앤파커스 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791165343477
정가: 16,800원 / 판매가: 15,120원 / 마일리지: 65원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




‘세계에서 가장 큰 나라는 어디일까?’라는 질문에 ‘러시아? 캐나다?’를 생각했다면 지리적 상상력 업데이트가 시급하다. 미래의 지도를 읽을 줄 아는 사람은 유튜브, 구글, 아미(ARMY)라고 답할 것이다. 전 세계에서 코로나19 탈출에 가장 앞선 두 나라, 영국과 이스라엘은 공통점이 있다. 바로 현장 중심, 지도 중심의 문제해결 능력이 뛰어나다는 것이다. 

영국은 전통적인 지도 강국으로 1800년대 콜레라가 창궐했을 때도 지도를 통해 솔루션을 찾았고, 이스라엘 청년들은 어려서부터 ‘스트리트 스마트’를 배우고 ‘빅 트립’으로 세계 무대를 미리 체험하며 지리적 감각을 익힌다.

이 책은 ‘지도력(地圖力…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The ‘Global Sanctions Data Base’: Mapping international sanction policies from 1950-2019]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/global-sanctions-data-base-mapping-international-sanction-policies-1950-2019</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/global-sanctions-data-base-mapping-international-sanction-policies-1950-2019"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the world experienced a golden age of international economic integration in the 1990s and the 2000s, in the more recent past there has been an emergence of interstate political conflicts, political polarisation, and extensive use of coercive sanctions intended to limit the international movement of goods, assets, and people. This column presents findings from the newly updated Global Sanctions Data Base, which now includes the years of the Trump presidency and provides a more comprehensive coverage of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel  Felbermayr, Aleksandra Kirilakha, Constantinos Syropoulos, Erdal Yalcin, Yoto  Yotov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerating the production of Covid-19 vaccines: The role of adjustment costs]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/content/accelerating-production-covid-19-vaccines-role-adjustment-costs</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/content/accelerating-production-covid-19-vaccines-role-adjustment-costs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experience with Covid-19 has shown how vaccinating the population as quickly as possible can be of paramount importance, however with fixed contracts the benefits for early delivery of such vaccines are huge for society, but non-existent for suppliers. Daniel Gros (Centre for European Policy Studies) talks to Tim Philips about why vaccine contracts should have incentives for accelerated production built into them.
The paper discussed can be found here:
Covid Economics Issue 77: Incentives for accelerating t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Gros</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why global uncertainty is declining]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/why-global-uncertainty-declining</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/why-global-uncertainty-declining"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest update of the World Uncertainty Index indicates that global uncertainty has fallen back to its long-run average after reaching a historical high in 2020. This column describes how this is driven by a significant decline in two key drivers of global uncertainty over the last few years: US–China trade tensions and Brexit negotiations. A sub-index of the World Uncertainty Index, the World Pandemic Uncertainty Index, reveals that uncertainty related to COVID-19 is also starting to subside, especially…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hites Ahir, Nicholas Bloom, Davide Furceri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well-being and poverty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/povety-well-being-work-incentives</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/povety-well-being-work-incentives"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Policymakers often evaluate anti-poverty programs by just one measure—income. A paper in the American Economic Journal: Microeconomics says well-being is important to consider, too.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[누가 내 돈을 훔쳐갔을까?/이재광 지음/한국전자도서출판(주)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271642219</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271642219"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[누가 내 돈을 훔쳐갔을까?
이재광 지음 / 한국전자도서출판(주) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791186799475
정가: 16,800원 / 판매가: 15,120원 / 마일리지: 61원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




누가 내 돈을 훔쳐갔을까? 내 돈을 훔쳐가는 것은 다름아닌 나의 무지와 무관심이다. 금융 전문가인 저자는 모든 것이 그렇지만 특히 금융은 겉으로 보이는 것이 다가 아니며, 이면에 감춰진 위험을 찾으려 노력해야 한다고 말한다. 

수익을 추구할 수밖에 없는 금융기관에 관대함과 배려심을 기대해서는 안 되고, 애써 모은 돈을 스스로 지키기 위한 지식과 관심의 필요성을 강조한다. 경제 금융 EQ를 키워야만 살아남을 수 있는 시대가 된 것이다. 

금융의 기본에서부터 금융상품에 투자하려면 알아야 하는 것, 연금과 국민연금 그리고 퇴직연금, 주식과 부동산 투자에 이르기까지, 평범한 모두의 행복한 미래를 위해 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go 마스터하기 2/e/미할리스 추칼로스 지음, 남기혁 옮김/에이콘출판]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271640903</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271640903"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Go 마스터하기 2/e
미할리스 추칼로스 지음, 남기혁 옮김 / 에이콘출판 / 2021년 06월 / ISBN:9791161755311
정가: 50,000원 / 판매가: 45,000원 / 마일리지: 222원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




Go 언어의 기본 개념부터 동시성, 네트워크, 머신러닝, 고급 데이터 구조에 이르기까지 방대한 주제를 실습 예제와 함께 소개한다. 1판의 내용 중 도커와 쿠버네티스, 깃, 웹어셈블리, JSON, gRPC 등을 보강했으며, 머신러닝 관련 내용을 새롭게 추가했다. 이 책을 통해 Go 언어의 기초뿐만 아니라, 실전에서 활용할 수 있는 다양한 기술을 배울 수 있다. Go 언어를 제대로 배우고 싶다면 이 책은 전문가 수준에 이르기 위한 필독서다.


1장. Go와 OS

__Go 언어의 역사
__Go 현황
__Go 언어의 장점
____Go 언어는 완벽한가?
______전처리기란?
____godoc 유틸리티
__Go 코드 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[지역화폐가 대안이다/양준호.신규철.남창섭 지음/인천출판사]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271630944</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271630944"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[지역화폐가 대안이다
양준호.신규철.남창섭 지음 / 인천출판사 / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9788996177319
정가: 20,000원 / 판매가: 18,000원 / 마일리지: 76원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




최근에는 민간이 주도하면 지역화폐, 지자체가 주도하면 지역사랑상품권이라는 그동안의 구분이 무의미해졌다. 이를 바탕으로 이 책에서 사용되는 지역사랑상품권과 지역화폐는 다른 개념이 아니다. 사실상 같은 개념으로 이해할 수 있다. 

다만 그동안 재래시장 등에서 제한적으로 사용되던 지역사랑상품권과는 달리 사용금액의 일정비율을 캐시백으로 돌려주면서 폭발적인 인기를 끌고 있는 인천e음을 지역화폐로 명칭을 통일하고자 한다.

머리말

1장 지금 왜 지역화폐인가
 
 - 지역화폐 전성시대
 - 지금, 왜 지역화폐인가?
 - 역외소비를 막아라
 - 지역순환형경제의 출발점
 - 지역화폐 전국을 휩쓸다

…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[불만 시대의 자본주의/조지프 스티글리츠 지음, 박세연 옮김/열린책들]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271629775</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271629775"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[불만 시대의 자본주의
조지프 스티글리츠 지음, 박세연 옮김 / 열린책들 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788932921051
정가: 23,000원 / 판매가: 20,700원 / 마일리지: 90원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




<우리 시대는 너무 많은 이들이 다른 이의 몫을 빼앗음으로써 부를 쌓고 있다.> 노벨 경제학상 수상자이자 컬럼비아 대학교 석좌 교수 조지프 스티글리츠가 신간 『불만 시대의 자본주의』에서 미국식 시장 경제는 실패했다고 정면으로 비판한다. 

그는 금융화, 세계화, 기업의 독점화(스티글리츠의 3가지 핵심 연구 주제)가 거대한 불평등을 낳고 있으며, 금융 산업과 몇몇 기업이 경제 전반을 장악하고 불공정한 규칙을 통해 막대한 부를 쌓고 있다고 주장한다. 이 책은 정부의 강력한 개입만이 국가의 진정한 부(富)를 늘리고, 오늘날 자본주의가 처한 위기를 풀 수 있다고 강조한다. 

스티글리츠에 따르면, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Default expectations and currency movements]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/default-expectations-and-currency-movements</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/default-expectations-and-currency-movements"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In fixed exchange rate systems, default risks tend to have devastating effects on currencies, usually leading to sharp devaluations. However, little is known about the relationship between default expectations and exchange rates in floating rate regimes. This column uses data from a broad set of currencies to uncover a strong link between exchange rate movements and sovereign risk across all exchange rate regimes. This relationship is largely caused by countries’ exposure to global sovereign risk factors an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pasquale Della Corte, Lucio  Sarno, Maik Schmeling, Christian Wagner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Human capital, working time flexibility and discrimination in the gender wage gap]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/human-capital-working-time-flexibility-and-discrimination-gender-wage-gap</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/human-capital-working-time-flexibility-and-discrimination-gender-wage-gap"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite progress in recent decades, women in Europe still earn roughly 15% less per hour than similarly qualified men. This column uses individual-level data to analyse the drivers of gender wage gaps and finds that in Northern and Western Europe the gap is largely a consequence of childbirth (a ‘glass ceiling’), while in Central and Eastern Europe it is due more to social norms, gender stereotyping, and discrimination (or ‘sticky floors’). Closing gender wage gaps will thus require policies tailored to the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele Ciminelli, Cyrille Schwellnus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit deterred international students from applying to UK universities]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/brexit-deterred-international-students-applying-uk-universities</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/brexit-deterred-international-students-applying-uk-universities"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attracting international students is critical for public universities in the UK increasingly facing funding cuts and a diminishing domestic youth population. This column discusses how Brexit may have affected students’ willingness to study in the UK and the factors likely driving the students’ choices. Brexit significantly lowered applications from EU students, especially for science, technology, engineering and mathematics subjects and for more selective institutions. International student enrolments also …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Catalina Amuedo-Dorantes, Agnese Romiti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[금융소비자보호/조남희 지음/연암사]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271497020</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271497020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T05:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[금융소비자보호
조남희 지음 / 연암사 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791155580950
정가: 28,000원 / 판매가: 28,000원 / 마일리지: 137원
이벤트: 수험서.외국어.컴퓨터.대학교재-오거나이저+스티커/텀블러/젤펜/펜 파우치




2021년 3월 25일 시행된 금융소비자보호법(금소법) 관련 정책과 규정, 사례 등을 집대성한 책이다. 금융소비자에 대한 올바른 인식과 종합적인 보호체계를 수립하는 데 도움이 될 수 있도록 집필하였다. 금융소비자보호를 위한 막연한 논쟁 대신 금융당국, 금융회사, 금융소비자가 구체적으로 무엇을 해야 하는지를 명쾌하게 보여준다.

머리말 _ 5

제 1 장 금융소비자란 누구인가?

1. 금융소비자 정의 _ 17
2. 금융소비자보호 필요성 _ 20
3. 금융소비자보호 영역 _ 22
4. 금융소비자보호 체계 _ 23
5. 주요 선진국 금융소비자보호 기구 _ 26
6. 우리나라 금융소비자보호 기구 _ 32
7. 금융소비자보호 추세 _ 34
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frontmatter of Econometrica Vol. 89 Iss. 3]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA893FM</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA893FM?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page i-ii, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forthcoming Papers]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA893FORTH</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA893FORTH?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1507-1507, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backmatter of Econometrica Vol. 89 Iss. 3]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA893BM</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA893BM?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page iii-v, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Econometric Society 2020 Annual Report of the President]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA893PRES</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA893PRES?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1509-1518, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reply to: Comments on “General Equilibrium Oligopoly and Ownership Structure”]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA18868</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA18868?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1061-1063, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Azar, 
Xavier Vives</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Comment on: “General Equilibrium Oligopoly and Ownership Structure” by José Azar and Xavier Vives]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA18810</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA18810?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1049-1053, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Eeckhout</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Comment on: “General Equilibrium Oligopoly and Ownership Structure” by José Azar and Xavier Vives]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA18862</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA18862?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1055-1059, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Philippon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nash Equilibria on (Un)Stable Networks]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA12576</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA12576?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1179-1206, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anton Badev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Macroeconomic Model With Financially Constrained Producers and Intermediaries]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA16438</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA16438?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1361-1418, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vadim Elenev, 
Tim Landvoigt, 
Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General Equilibrium Oligopoly and Ownership Structure]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA17906</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA17906?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 999-1048, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Azar, 
Xavier Vives</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Limit Points of Endogenous Misspecified Learning]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA18508</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA18508?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1065-1098, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Drew Fudenberg, 
Giacomo Lanzani, 
Philipp Strack</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salvaging Falsified Instrumental Variable Models]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA17969</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA17969?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1449-1469, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew A. Masten, 
Alexandre Poirier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Auction Design With Common Values: An Informationally Robust Approach]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA16297</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA16297?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1313-1360, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Brooks, 
Songzi Du</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asset Pricing With Endogenously Uninsurable Tail Risk]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA15142</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA15142?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1471-1505, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hengjie Ai, 
Anmol Bhandari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viability and Arbitrage Under Knightian Uncertainty]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA16535</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA16535?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1207-1234, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matteo Burzoni, 
Frank Riedel, 
H. Mete Soner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aggregate Dynamics in Lumpy Economies]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA17344</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA17344?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1235-1264, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac Baley, 
Andrés Blanco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Screening in Vertical Oligopolies]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA17016</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA17016?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1265-1311, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hector Chade, 
Jeroen Swinkels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inference for Iterated GMM Under Misspecification]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA16274</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA16274?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1419-1447, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bruce E. Hansen, 
Seojeong Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Asset Management Contracts With Hidden Savings]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA14929</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA14929?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1099-1139, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sebastian Di Tella, 
Yuliy Sannikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finite‐Sample Optimal Estimation and Inference on Average Treatment Effects Under Unconfoundedness]]></title>
        <id>10.3982/ECTA16907</id>
        <link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3982/ECTA16907?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Econometrica, Volume 89, Issue 3, Page 1141-1177, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timothy B. Armstrong, 
Michal Kolesár</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free trade agreements do not always ensure free trade]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/free-trade-agreements-do-not-always-ensure-free-trade</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/free-trade-agreements-do-not-always-ensure-free-trade"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The changes in the UK’s trading relationship with the EU are likely to have widespread effects, many of which are yet to be understood in full. This column introduces the issue of compliance with rules of origin requirements within free trade agreements. The authors argue that complying with these rules can present firms with additional production costs that would not have been present had the UK remained a part of the EU.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan I. Haaland, Ian  Wooton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The government as an (effective) venture capitalist]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/government-effective-venture-capitalist</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/government-effective-venture-capitalist"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government funding to boost innovation has seen an uplift since the unfolding of the COVID crisis. Using extensive global data, this column examines how government funding programmes focused on early-stage companies interact with private capital markets, and finds a positive relationship between government funding at this business stage and private capital allocation. Increased reliance on private capital markets enabled governments to mitigate investment frictions, improve capital allocation, and thereby i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Bai, Shai Bernstein, Abhishek Dev, Josh Lerner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[메이저리그 야구 통계학 2/e/김재민 지음/에이콘출판]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271461220</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271461220"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T08:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[메이저리그 야구 통계학 2/e
김재민 지음 / 에이콘출판 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791161755236
정가: 33,000원 / 판매가: 29,700원 / 마일리지: 135원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




메이저리그에서 지난 140년 동안 통계원의 손으로 시작해, 90년대 퀘스텍(QuesTec), 2000년대 PITCHf/x, 2010년대 아마존과 파트너쉽을 통한 트랙맨 플랫폼까지 상상 이상의 야구 데이터가 수집돼 왔다. 

장구한 메이저리그 데이터의 힘을 빌려 전통적 분석인 상관관계 분석, 분산분석, 회귀분석, 로지스틱 회귀분석, 계량경제학 패널데이터 분석과 최근 머신러닝으로 다시 관심을 받고 있는 군집분석, 요인분석, 지도학습, 딥러닝 기반 자연어처리를 통해 야구 이야기를 모델링하고 직접 테스트한다. 모든 작업에는 학계와 산업계 분석 작업에 이미 중심이 된 오픈소스 통계 프로그램 R을 사용한다.

데이터 분석 목적은 데이터를 통해 현실을…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[메타버스 새로운 기회/김상균.신병호 지음/베가북스]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271457429</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271457429"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T07:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[메타버스 새로운 기회
김상균.신병호 지음 / 베가북스 / 2021년 06월 / ISBN:9791190242868
정가: 18,800원 / 판매가: 16,920원 / 마일리지: 73원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




디지털 지구를 처음 국내 대중에게 알린 메타버스의 선구자인 김상균은 『메타버스 새로운 기회』를 통해 메타버스란 무엇이고 앞으로 메타버스가 나아갈 방향을 설명하여 많은 사람들에게 새로운 지구에 사는 방법과 미래를 거머쥘 비책을 전달한다. 

김상균은 메타버스를 우리의 삶과 사회를 새롭게 바라보게 만들어주는 렌즈에 비유하면서 그 렌즈를 통해 세상의 요동치는 변화 속에서 우리가 새로운 기회를 놓치지 않고 메타버스 시대를 이끌어 갈 수 있는 전략을 제시한다. 

그는 “메타버스 시대에는 비즈니스 형태가 대번혁이 일어날 것이고 이는 기업들의 퀀텀점프의 기회가 될 것”이라고 말했다. 또한 “현재의 흐름이 과거 인터넷, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js 디자인 패턴 바이블/Mario Casciaro.Luciano Mammino 지음, 김성원 외 옮김/영진.com(영진닷컴)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271440148</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271440148"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T05:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js 디자인 패턴 바이블
Mario Casciaro.Luciano Mammino 지음, 김성원 외 옮김 / 영진.com(영진닷컴) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788931464283
정가: 32,000원 / 판매가: 28,800원 / 마일리지: 134원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




완벽한 Node.js 애플리케이션 설계를 위한 디자인 패턴 바이블. Node.js로 프로그래밍을 하는데 필요한 기초적인 개념을 시작으로 시작으로 웹 애플리케이션을 만드는데 사용할 수 있는 디자인 패턴까지, 직접 따라할 수 있는 예제와 모범 사례들을 통해 살펴본다.

각 챕터는 디자인 패턴을 주제별로 나누어 상황에 따른 디자인 패턴과 이용 사례를 소개한다. 또한 설명에서 사용되었던 사례에 따라 실제 개발 환경에서 사용할 수 있는 다양한 라이브러리와 기술들을 소개하며 Node.js의 전체적인 생태계와 솔루션과 조명한다.


Chapter 01 Node.js 플랫폼…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[외국환거래실무/김병섭 외 지음/한국금융연수원]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271437072</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271437072"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T04:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[외국환거래실무
김병섭 외 지음 / 한국금융연수원 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788928726660
정가: 21,000원 / 판매가: 21,000원 / 마일리지: 107원
이벤트: 수험서.외국어.컴퓨터.대학교재-오거나이저+스티커/텀블러/젤펜/펜 파우치




본 서는 일반적 마케팅 전략 및 개념을 소개하고 일선 영업점에서 외환상품의 마케팅 분석, 전략을 사례 형태로 작성하였으며, 외환섭외의 일반적인 방법을 소개하였다. 또한 외환상품, 외환거래와 서비스, 최근 다양하게 출시되는 해외펀드, 외화관련 채권, 파생연계상품 등을 소개하였다. 상품의 소개는 기본적 상품컨셉이해를 위한 개념 의 소개와, 최근 상품 트렌드 이해를 돕는데 중점을 두었다.

제1장 은행 및 본지점 간 외환실무

제2장 대고객 외환실무

제3장 특수한 외환상품

제4장 외국환회계

제5장 외국환업무와 관련된 컴플라이언스업무

제6장 외국환거래관련 위규사례


국내도서 > 대학교재/전문서적 > 경상계열 > 재무/금융
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[대충 알고 잘은 모르는 부의 상식/심재성 지음/지식과감성#]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271418669</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271418669"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T00:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[대충 알고 잘은 모르는 부의 상식
심재성 지음 / 지식과감성# / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791165528270
정가: 15,000원 / 판매가: 13,500원 / 마일리지: 55원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




부자의 조건이 단순히 물질적인 부의 축적만을 가지고 평가하고 평가받을 수는 없을 것이다. 부라고 하는 것이 가치중립적이라면 그러한 부를 축적하고 소비하는 부자는 천박할 수도 훌륭할 수도 있다.

1장 자산소득이 노동소득을 넘어설 때 
01 시작은 빠를수록 좋다
02 라이프스타일과 일개미 
03 상대적 가난
04 부자의 조건
05 부자로 가는 길 
06 월급쟁이가 부자 되기
07 자신의 노력으로 부의 추월차선 올라타기
08 하루라도 빨리 은퇴하자 

2장 위기가 결국 기회였다
01 위기는 늘 공포스럽다
02 위기의 시그널 1
03 위기의 시그널 2
04 위기의 시그널 3 
05 위기…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender role norms and mothers' labour supply]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/gender-role-norms-and-mothers-labour-supply</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/gender-role-norms-and-mothers-labour-supply"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite a significant reduction in gender differences in the labour market over the last 40 years, they are still present in most advanced economies and do not appear likely to vanish soon. This column analyses the impact of culture, defined by women’s gender role attitudes, on maternal labour market decisions. It finds that social pressure is at least as strong as social learning in influencing labour market behaviour. Once these channels are accounted for, there is no direct effect of peers’ gender identi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danilo  Cavapozzi, Marco Francesconi, Cheti  Nicoletti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cooperation among people with different cognitive skill levels]]></title>
        <id>https://voxeu.org/article/cooperation-among-people-different-cognitive-skill-levels</id>
        <link href="https://voxeu.org/article/cooperation-among-people-different-cognitive-skill-levels"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A large part of social interaction occurs among very different individuals. Characteristics such as trust, altruism, and intelligence can have important effects on strategic behaviour. This column studies how interactions between groups with different cognitive skill levels affect cooperation. Using an indefinitely repeated Prisoner’s Dilemma game, it finds that integrating players with different abilities leads to higher cooperation rates and higher aggregate payoffs than when they play separately. This is…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eugenio Proto, Aldo Rustichini, Andis Sofianos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[American capitalism and incarceration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/private-prisons-time-served-recidivism-mississippi</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/private-prisons-time-served-recidivism-mississippi"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inmates sent to private prisons serve 90 extra days on average, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Economic Policy. We spoke author Anita Mukherjee about why that is and how private prison contracting could be reformed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[아베노믹스와 저온호황/이창민 지음/제이앤씨]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271377888</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271377888"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T06:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[아베노믹스와 저온호황
이창민 지음 / 제이앤씨 / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9791159171758
정가: 9,000원 / 판매가: 8,550원 / 마일리지: 38원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




서울대학교 일본연구소 ReadingJapan 32권. 일본경제사라는 관점에서 아베노믹스는 훗날 어떠한 평가를 받게 될 것인가? 이 책에는 지난 7년 8개월간의 아베노믹스에 대한 역사적 평가를 시도한다.

1. 아베노믹스 경기의 종언(終焉)	   
2. 아베노믹스의 탄생 
3. 장기불황에서 탈출하였는가? 
4. 화살은 적중하였는가? 
5. 경로는 작동하였는가? 
6. 아베노믹스를 둘러싼 퍼즐 
7. 저온호황의 시대 
종합토론 
참고문헌


국내도서 > 경제경영 > 경제학/경제일반 > 경제사/경제전망 > 아시아 경제사/경제전망]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[네카쿠배 경제학/김철민 지음/페이지2(page2)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271354671</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271354671"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T02:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[네카쿠배 경제학
김철민 지음 / 페이지2(page2) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791190977227
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 58원
이벤트: 코스피/엑셀/네넵 스티커 (대상도서 포함 국내도서 2만원 이상)




어느새 전화 주문보다 앱 주문이, 매장 쇼핑보다 온라인 쇼핑이 익숙해진 요즘이다. 시대가 바뀌면 생활이 바뀌고 생활이 바뀌면 시장이 바뀐다. 네이버, 쿠팡, 카카오, 배달의민족, 마켓컬리, 무신사, 오늘의집, 당근마켓 등은 IT기술을 기반으로 현대인의 라이프 스타일을 바꾸고 있는 국내 대표 이커머스이자 온디맨드 서비스 사업자다. 오프라인 시장에서 온라인 시장으로의 소비자 이동은 이미 몇 년 전에 시작됐지만 코로나19 이후로 그 속도가 십수 년 빨라졌다.

온라인 마켓이 쑥쑥 성장한들 팔리는 상품은 모두 배달과 배송이라는 오프라인 공간과 물리적 이동을 거쳐야 한다. 그런데 사람들은 원산지 확인은 꼼꼼히 하면서 어떻게 그 물건이 그곳까지 왔는지에…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[반전의 경제학/최병서 지음/나무나무]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271311320</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271311320"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T06:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[반전의 경제학
최병서 지음 / 나무나무 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788998529260
정가: 17,000원 / 판매가: 15,300원 / 마일리지: 62원
이벤트: 코스피/엑셀/네넵 스티커 (대상도서 포함 국내도서 2만원 이상)




우리가 알고 있는 상식을 팩트를 사용해서 뒤집는다. 각 꼭지의 길이는 단숨에 읽을 수 있는 정도의 양이며, 짧은 글에 핵심만 정리했고 경제학자의 눈으로 본 ‘세상이 움직이는 방식’을 냉철하게 보여준다. 또한 우리가 아는 상식과는 다른 이유로 세상이 움직이는 다양한 사례를 제시한다. 당연한 것 같은 이야기 뒷면에 숨어 있는 당연하지 않은 의외성이 돋보인다.

책머리에 경제학은 인간 본성을 탐구한다
1부 사람의 목숨값은 얼마일까
01 한국의 부모가 자녀와 만나는 횟수를 늘리는 유일한 변수는 ‘돈’이다
02 우리는 당신들(부모)의 빚을 갚지 않겠다
03 섹스와 소득의 상관관계 
04 비아그라 효과와 브라질 연금
05 인도의 도시락 배달: 다바왈라
06 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[케인스는 어떻게 재정을 파탄냈는가/제임스 뷰캐넌.존 버튼.리차드 와그너 지음, 옥동석 옮김/자유기업원]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271300550</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271300550"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T05:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[케인스는 어떻게 재정을 파탄냈는가
제임스 뷰캐넌.존 버튼.리차드 와그너 지음, 옥동석 옮김 / 자유기업원 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788984291935
정가: 14,000원 / 판매가: 14,000원 / 마일리지: 63원
이벤트: 수험서.외국어.컴퓨터.대학교재-오거나이저+스티커/텀블러/젤펜/펜 파우치




케인스가 주장한 수정자본주의의 문제점을 낱낱이 해체하고, 재정준칙이라는 견제 장치의 도입을 통해 ‘정치의 경제학’에 대한 방향성을 제시한다. 정부의 경제 개입은 재정 적자의 남용과 포퓰리즘을 야기한다는 케인스 재정이론의 숨겨진 이면을 폭로하고 정부를 견제할 재정준칙 도입을 호소한다.

역자 서문
추천사
요약

제Ⅰ부 케인시안 재정, 대체 무엇이 문제였나?
1. 케인시안, 고전파의 세계관을 바꾸다
2. 현실과 동떨어진 재정정책
3. 민주주의에 대한 무지
4. 케인시안 정치곡해의 파멸적 결과
5. 케인시안은 민주주의를 병들게 한다

제Ⅱ부 '위대한 영국'에서 ‘바보 같은 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[핏팅 코리아/정영록 지음/하다(HadA)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271297891</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271297891"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T04:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[핏팅 코리아
정영록 지음 / 하다(HadA) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788997170630
정가: 15,000원 / 판매가: 13,500원 / 마일리지: 58원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




현재 대한민국과 주변국의 정세를 살피며 현 상황에 꼭 맞는 획기적인 경제정책을 제시한다. 이성적인 판단으로 명분이나 이해관계보다는 실리를 추구한다. 대한민국만의 미래 전략 자산과 생애주기형 정책, 청년 세대를 위한 사회공공서비스 등 우리 사회에 필요한 정책에 더해 타당성 여부까지 논하며 신뢰성을 더한다. 이와 함께 세대별 역할을 제시하고, 이를 통한 갈등 완화, 우리 사회가 나아가야 할 바람직한 방향을 살펴본다.

대한민국 살리는 동발적 경제정책 제안
국민국가를 넘어 알짜국가로 ‘대한민국 4.0을 위하여’

PART 01 중국은 미국을 뛰어넘을 수 있을까
1_ 국민국가 경쟁 300년
세계적 대전환
범세계적 전통적 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[School spending matters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/state-education-spending-recession-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/state-education-spending-recession-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recession-induced cuts to school spending had lasting ill-effects on test scores and college enrollment, especially in states where schools rely more heavily on state aid, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Economic Policy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[나도 돈 벌고 싶다/SBS스페셜 제작팀.이큰별 지음/그린하우스]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271240240</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271240240"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T05:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[나도 돈 벌고 싶다
SBS스페셜 제작팀.이큰별 지음 / 그린하우스 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791190419291
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 61원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




바야흐로 스타트업 전성시대이다. 여러 매체에서 스타트업 성공신화를 다루고 정부 산하 기관들은 각종 창업 지원 정책을 내놓는다. 중소벤처기업부에 따르면 30세 미만 신설법인 대표의 수는 해마다 증가하고 있다. 젊고 걸출한 CEO의 성공담을 보고 접하며, 청년들은 오늘도 창업을 한다. 세상을 바꾸리라는 일념 하나로 한 치 앞도 보이지 않는 바다를 항해하는 것이다. 그리고 개중에는 계속되는 취업난, 고용불안으로 창업에 눈을 돌리는 이들도 있다. 직장이 본인의 인생을 보장해주지 않는다는 이유에서다. 

<SBS 스페셜 체인져스 - 나도 돈 벌고 싶다>는 ‘모두가 어렵다고 말하는 시대에도 분명 누군가는 돈을 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[화폐의 비밀/제라르 푸셰 지음, 서익진.김준강 옮김/길(도서출판)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271235728</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271235728"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T05:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[화폐의 비밀
제라르 푸셰 지음, 서익진.김준강 옮김 / 길(도서출판) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788964452363
정가: 22,000원 / 판매가: 19,800원 / 마일리지: 91원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




왜 우리는 늘 돈이 부족하다고 느낄까? 왜 오늘날에는 가정을 유지하기 위해 두 가지 이상의 일을 해야만 하는 사람들이 많을까? 공공 서비스는 축소 경향을 보이는데 세금은 왜 오히려 늘어날까? 어떤 사람은 아무 일 하지 않아도 부유해지는 반면, 어떤 사람은 온종일 힘들게 일해도 먹고살기 바쁜 까닭은 무엇일까? 지금 우리가 살아가고 있는 자본주의의 다양한 단면들이자 누구나 피부로 느끼는 자본주의의 모순들이다.

이러한 사회, 즉 인간이 만들어냈고 그 속에서 살아가고 있는 이 체제는 정확히 자본주의 시장경제 체제이다. 그 체제를 움직이게 하는 한 요소가 있으니, 그것이 바로 ‘화폐’이다. 화폐가 없으면…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asset Pricing with Omitted Factors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714090?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714090?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T03:50:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Giglio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[팀 하포드의 세상을 바꾼 51가지 물건/팀 하포드 지음, 김태훈 옮김/세종(세종서적)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=271217486</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=271217486"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[팀 하포드의 세상을 바꾼 51가지 물건
팀 하포드 지음, 김태훈 옮김 / 세종(세종서적) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788984078109
정가: 19,000원 / 판매가: 17,100원 / 마일리지: 71원
이벤트: 코스피/엑셀/네넵 스티커 (대상도서 포함 국내도서 2만원 이상)




넷플릭스와 스트리밍 서비스의 시작이 재봉틀이라면 믿겨지는가? 요즘의 인플루언서 협찬이 웨지우드사의 크림색 티세트에서 시작되었다면 어떤가? 브랜드의 이미지를 만들고 고객과 소통하는 브랜드 마케팅은 어떻게 시작되었을까? 베스트셀러 작가이자 경제학자인 팀 하포드는 우리가 현재 누리는 모든 것들에 대해 51가지 물건으로 답한다.

연필, 튤립, 웨지우드사의 크림색 티세트, 담배, 재봉틀은 어떻게 세상을 변화시켰을까? 이것들이 없었다면 연필에서 비롯된 국제적인 공급사슬과 정밀한 제조법도, 가격 시스템, 웨지우드사의 티세트에서 비롯된 유명인 협찬도, 담배에서 비롯된 브랜드 마케팅, 재봉틀에서 비롯된 렌털 서비스와 나아…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Captive shoppers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/jerusalem-city-prices-supermarkets</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/jerusalem-city-prices-supermarkets"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why do the poor pay more? A paper in the American Economic Journal: Economic Policy investigates how socioeconomic standing interacts with spatial frictions among supermarket shoppers in Jerusalem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decomposing news shocks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/oil-supply-news-opec-announcements</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/oil-supply-news-opec-announcements"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Production announcements from OPEC have a profound impact on oil prices and the US economy, even when current oil supplies don’t change, according to a paper in the American Economic Reviewg.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taxation under Learning by Doing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713745?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713745?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T04:14:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miltiadis Makris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Face-to-Face Communication in Organizations]]></title>
        <id>https://microeconomicinsights.org/?p=2935</id>
        <link href="https://microeconomicinsights.org/face-to-face-communication-in-organizations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T09:16:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The international response to the COVID-19 pandemic has emphasised working from home, especially for office workers tasked with the generation and processing of information. Compliance has generally been very high, with most companies not just encouraging, but mandating, their employees to work from home. This has led to an emptying of city centres and financial […]
The post Face-to-Face Communication in Organizations appeared first on Microeconomic Insights.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Catling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C#을 다루는 기술/존 스킷 지음, 김명신 옮김/길벗]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270856977</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270856977"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T07:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[C#을 다루는 기술
존 스킷 지음, 김명신 옮김 / 길벗 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791165215521
정가: 36,000원 / 판매가: 32,400원 / 마일리지: 156원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




C#을 C#답게 사용하자! 200개의 예제로 실습하며 배우는 간결하고 효과적인 C# 작성법! 이 책의 목표는 여러분이 C#을 최대한 편안하게 사용하도록 하는 것이다. C#의 주요 기능을 다루는 것은 물론이고, 그 내부 동작 방식을 C# 전문가인 저자만의 경험과 매력적인 통찰로 담아내 C#을 C#답게 사용하도록 돕는다. 또한, 200개가 넘는 현실적인 예제를 통해 문제를 해결하고 생산성 높은 코드를 작성하는 방법을 알려준다.

1부 C#에 대해서 

1장 C# 개발자로 살아남기 
1.1 진화하는 언어 
__1.1.1 어떤 규모의 응용프로그램에도 유용한 타입 시스템 
__1.1.2 더욱 간결한 코드 작성 
__1.1.3 LINQ를 이용한 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 2학년 데이터 분석 구조/모리 요시나오 지음, 오윤기 외 옮김/성안당]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270853220</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270853220"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T06:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python 2학년 데이터 분석 구조
모리 요시나오 지음, 오윤기 외 옮김 / 성안당 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788931557275
정가: 17,000원 / 판매가: 15,300원 / 마일리지: 65원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




Python 학습을 시작한 지 얼마 안 된 초보자로서 ‘다음 단계로 무엇을 해야 할지 모르겠다, Python의 기본은 알고 있지만 좀 더 실용적인 프로그램을 만들어 보고 싶다’는 생각을 하고 있는 분들이 많을 것이다. 이 책은 그런 생각을 하는 Python 초보자들이 다음 단계로 데이터 분석에 도전하기 위한 책이다.

<Python 2학년 스크래핑 구조>에서는 인터넷에서 여러 형식의 데이터를 모으거나 읽는 구조와 방법에 대해서 설명했다. 이 책에서는 수집한 데이터를 어떻게 다룰지에 대해 설명한다. 표준편차는 어떻게 사용하는지? 정규분포는 어떤 것인지? 등에 대해 수식을 사용하지 않고 Python으로 쉽게 설명한다.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[30일 역전의 경제학/오영수 지음/이담북스]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270848733</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270848733"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[30일 역전의 경제학
오영수 지음 / 이담북스 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791166033995
정가: 18,000원 / 판매가: 16,200원 / 마일리지: 75원
이벤트: 코스피/엑셀/네넵 스티커 (대상도서 포함 국내도서 2만원 이상)




오랜 시간 경제를 가르쳐 온 오영수 교수의 ≪30일 역전의 경제학≫이 개정판으로 돌아왔다. 이 책은 경제학 입문서로 다양한 실제 사례와 더불어 영화, 고전문학, 사회적 이슈 등을 화두로 삼아 딱딱한 경제학을 친근하게 풀어냈다. 그러면서도 꼭 알아야 할 주요 개념만을 엄선해서 담았으니 이 책 한 권이면 경제학 개념과 원리는 물론 경제학적 사고의 틀이 향상되어 있는 자신을 발견하게 될 것이다.

추천사 
시작하는 이야기 

PART 1. 기초개념
Day 1 욕망이라는 이름의 전차: 수요와 소비자잉여
Day 2 알파고와 이세돌: 합리적 선택과 한계 
Day 3 세상에 공짜는 없다: 기회비용
Day 4 뻥튀기 기계의 마술: 생산과 공급 
Day …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[이토록 쉬운 경제학/강영연 외 지음/한국경제신문]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270834219</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270834219"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T04:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[이토록 쉬운 경제학
강영연 외 지음 / 한국경제신문 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788947547154
정가: 18,000원 / 판매가: 16,200원 / 마일리지: 76원
이벤트:  기대평 남기면, 스타벅스 아메리카노 기프티콘 추첨




매주 토요일 <한국경제신문> 지면에 실렸던 ‘시네마노믹스’ 코너의 글들을 한 권의 책으로 묶은 것이다. 세계적으로 인기를 끈 대작부터 잘 알려지지 않은 독립영화까지 다양한 작품 50편을 아울렀다. 

<기생충>으로 세대 간 소득탄력성을 설명하고 <미안해요 리키>로 긱 이코노미를 설명한다. <아이리시맨>으로는 임금탄력성을, <라라랜드>로는 가격탄력성을, <극한직업>으로는 완전 경쟁시장과 독점적 경쟁시장을, <아메리칸 셰프>로는 밈노믹스를, <어벤져스>로는 인구경제학을 설명한다. 우리가 사랑하는 영화라는 매체를 통해 기회비용과 매몰비용부터 밴드왜건 효과와 외부 효과까지 수많은 경제학 용어를 헤집는다. 

누구나 책장 한 구석에는 두꺼운 책 한 권이 꽂혀 있…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C# 동시성 프로그래밍 2/e/스티븐 클리어리 지음, 김홍중 옮김/에이콘출판]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270818316</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270818316"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T02:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[C# 동시성 프로그래밍 2/e
스티븐 클리어리 지음, 김홍중 옮김 / 에이콘출판 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791161755274
정가: 30,000원 / 판매가: 27,000원 / 마일리지: 121원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




비동기, 병렬 처리, 데이터 흐름, 멀티스레딩 등 최신 닷넷 프레임워크와 C# 언어가 제공하는 동시성 기술과 함께 리액티브 프로그래밍, 동시성 기술의 상호운용, 동시 컬렉션, 테스트, 취소 기능, 동기화처럼 동시성과 관련이 있는 다양한 주제를 폭넓게 다룬다. 모든 주제를 간결하고 명확하게 설명하는 동시에 이해를 돕는 간단하고 효과적인 예제를 곁들여 동시성을 처음 접하거나 동시성에 익숙하지 않은 개발자를 동시성의 세계로 이끌어주는 훌륭한 안내서다.

1장. 동시성 개요 
__비동기 프로그래밍 
__병렬 프로그래밍 
__리액티브 프로그래밍 
__데이터 흐름 
__멀티스레드 프로그래밍
__동시성 애플리케이션용 컬렉션…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[뉴 맵/대니얼 예긴 지음, 우진하 옮김/리더스북]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270818177</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270818177"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T02:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[뉴 맵
대니얼 예긴 지음, 우진하 옮김 / 리더스북 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788901249605
정가: 29,000원 / 판매가: 26,100원 / 마일리지: 112원
이벤트: 화제의 책+알라딘 굿즈(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내도서 4만원 이상)




글로벌 베스트셀러 『황금의 샘(The Prize)』 저자 대니얼 예긴이 10년 만에 신작 『뉴 맵』으로 돌아왔다. 현대사와 자본주의의 흐름을 ‘석유’라는 스펙트럼으로 깊이 있게 분석해 전 세계 독자들의 뜨거운 찬사를 받았던 그가, 이번에는 ‘에너지’, ‘기후’, ‘지정학’이라는 보다 심층적인 키워드를 통해 부와 권력 그리고 기회가 어떻게 재편되고 있는지, 누가 새로운 시대의 주인공으로 부상할 것인지를 들려준다. 

오늘날 에너지는 세계 경제를 좌우하는 가장 영향력 있는 요소가 되어 국제 사회에서 나타나는 거의 모든 지정학적 갈등의 중심에 자리하고 있다. 2차 전지와 풍력, 태양광 등 신재생 에너지 시장은 코로나 이후 본격적으로 투자자들이 몰…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The effectiveness of HARP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/mortgage-refinances-debt-default-spending-harp</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/mortgage-refinances-debt-default-spending-harp"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Relaxing borrowing constraints on underwater homeowners was an important tool for relieving households after the Great Recession, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics. It may have made monetary policy more effective as well.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[한국경제 10대 전략/정판영 지음/생각나눔(기획실크)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270758875</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270758875"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T05:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[한국경제 10대 전략
정판영 지음 / 생각나눔(기획실크) / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791170482208
정가: 15,000원 / 판매가: 13,500원 / 마일리지: 60원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




왜 자유민주주의와 시장경제체제를 도입하면 민주화와 경제선진국이 될 수 있는가에 대한 이론과 실체를 분석하였다. 동시에 사회주의체제는 왜 경제선진국이 될 수 없다는 것을 분석하였다. 그뿐만 아니라 경제 중진국(중남미, 또는 지중해 연안국)도 사회주의체제와 포퓰리즘을 도입하면 국가가 어떻게 한결같이 붕괴되는지를 분석했다.

프롤로그
제1부 자유민주주의와 시장경제
제1장 자유민주주의 Liberal Democracy 自由民主主義
1. 자유민주주의란?
2. 자유민주의 기본질서(헌법적 가치 보장)
3. 자유민주주의는 어떻게 무너지는가?
4. 대한민국 자유민주주의 위기
5. 대북전단금지법과 미국 의회청문회
6.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Vietnamese Market/유영국 지음/클라우드나인]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270755958</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270755958"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T04:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Vietnamese Market
유영국 지음 / 클라우드나인 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791191334173
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 65원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




Preface	
Prologue	

Chapter 1 Vietnam--- Not, a Country I Thought It Was	

Introduction	

1.The History and Diplomatic Relations of Vietnam
Vietnam Has an Adversarial Relationship with China	
Vietnam is a Hegemonic Power on the Indochina Peninsula   
Stepping Out as a Dark Horse to Contain China With the US 
on Its Back	   …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[R Cookbook/J.D. 롱.폴 티터 지음, 이제원 옮김/인사이트]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270747254</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270747254"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T02:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[R Cookbook
J.D. 롱.폴 티터 지음, 이제원 옮김 / 인사이트 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9788966262984
정가: 35,000원 / 판매가: 31,500원 / 마일리지: 145원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




R은 통계, 그래픽 작업, 통계적 프로그래밍을 하는 데 매우 효과적인 툴로 통계 관련 작업을 하기 위해 필요한 모든 것을 제공하지만, 언어의 구조상 완전히 마스터하기는 어렵다. 이 책은 기본적인 태스크부터 입출력, 기초 통계, 그래픽, 그리고 선형회귀까지 폭넓게 다루고 있으며, 이 책에 수록되어 있는 태스크 중심의 레시피들은 R을 사용해서 곧바로 생산적인 일을 할 수 있게 도와줄 것이다. 

각각의 레시피는 특정한 '문제', '해결책'과 그것이 어떻게 동작하는지 설명하는 '논의' 섹션으로 구성되어 있다. R 입문자라면 기본기를 다질 수 있을 것이며, 중급 사용자라면 기억을 되짚어 주고 지평을 넓혀 줄 것이다. 특히 2판에서는 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[데이터가 뛰어노는 AI 놀이터, 캐글/가도와키 다이스케 외 지음, 대니얼WJ 옮김/한빛미디어]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270739663</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270739663"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T01:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[데이터가 뛰어노는 AI 놀이터, 캐글
가도와키 다이스케 외 지음, 대니얼WJ 옮김 / 한빛미디어 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791162244234
정가: 35,000원 / 판매가: 31,500원 / 마일리지: 139원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




데이터 분석 무한 경쟁 '캐글'에서 살아남기 위한 비결. 세계 최대 규모 데이터 분석 경진 대회 플랫폼인 캐글에서는 일반적이지 않은 데이터 처리 기법이 많이 활용된다. 이를 이해하고 체득하여 활용하는 것은 대회뿐만 아니라 데이터 분석 실무에서도 모델 정확도를 높이는 데 매우 유용하다. 

특징(feature)을 만드는 방법, 앙상블, 평가지표, 사이킷런, xgboost 등 기존에는 잘 다루지 않았던 기법과 사례를 이 책 한 권에 정리했다. 경진 대회에 참여할 계획이 있거나, 캐글을 경험해봤지만 더 높은 상위 랭킹에 도전하고 싶다면 지금 바로 읽어보기를 권한다. 


CHAPTER 1 경진 대회
1.1…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[주주 자본주의의 배신/린 스타우트 지음, 우희진 옮김/북돋움coop]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270736965</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270736965"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[주주 자본주의의 배신
린 스타우트 지음, 우희진 옮김 / 북돋움coop / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9791197142246
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 60원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




“기업의 목적은 주주 가치 극대화”라는 경영학의 기본 명제를 정면으로 반박하는 책. 경영학의 금과옥조로 여겨져온 이 명제가 사실은 기업법상의 근거가 없고, 이론적으로는 물론 실증 면에서도 오류가 드러났으며, 심지어 주주 자신에게조차 손해를 끼친다고 주장하며 주주 자본주의 정신을 근본적으로 뒤흔든다. 

저자에 의하면 주주 가치라는 개념은 기업법적으로나 경영학적으로, 또 철학적으로도 견고한 토대 없이 형성된 허상에 불과하다. 주주가 기업을 소유한다는 생각, 주주가 기업의 이익에 대해 유일한 잔여 청구권을 가진다는 생각, 주주가 주인으로서 경영진을 대리인으로 둔다는 생각은 모두 잘못됐다. 이것은 개…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[파이썬 챌린지/니콜라 레이시 지음, 황반석 옮김/제이펍]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270623315</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270623315"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T07:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[파이썬 챌린지
니콜라 레이시 지음, 황반석 옮김 / 제이펍 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791191600018
정가: 11,200원 / 판매가: 10,080원 / 마일리지: 46원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




매력적이면서도 독특한 구성의 이 가이드는 파이썬 기술을 단계별로 나누고 각 내용을 이해하기 쉬운 용어로 설명한다. 어려운 전문 용어들로 독자를 당황하게 하는 다른 책들과는 달리, 이 책은 독자의 손에 힘을 실어 줄 150개의 도전 과제를 담고 있다. 이들 과제를 해결하는 프로그램을 직접 작성해 봄으로써 코딩의 기초를 마스터할 수 있으며, 함수와 그래픽 유저 인터페이스를 사용하는 법, 그리고 텍스트, csv, SQL 파일에 링크하는 법 등을 빠르게 배울 수 있다.

옮긴이 머리말 _ vi 
이 책에 대하여 _ viii 
파이썬 다운로드하기 _ xi 
약간의 팁 _ xiii 
베타리더 후기 _ xv

파트 I 파이썬 배우기 _ 1
챌린지…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Impact of Temperature on Productivity and Labor Supply: Evidence from Indian Manufacturing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713733?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713733?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T04:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Somanathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[플랫폼 경제와 공짜 점심/강성호 지음/미디어숲]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270590904</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270590904"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T01:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[플랫폼 경제와 공짜 점심
강성호 지음 / 미디어숲 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791158741198
정가: 15,800원 / 판매가: 14,220원 / 마일리지: 63원
이벤트: 코스피/엑셀/네넵 스티커 (대상도서 포함 국내도서 2만원 이상)




우리는 초연결 사회에 살고 있다. 그저 사회과학 서적에 등장하는 막연한 개념이 아니다. 현재 우리는 눈을 뜨자마자 스마트폰으로 하루를 시작하고 네이버나 SNS를 통해 뉴스를 보고 댓글을 단다. 온라인 쇼핑몰에서 일상품을 구입하고 필요 없는 물품은 당근마켓에 판매하기도 한다. 또한 배달의민족을 통해 다양한 종류의 음식을 시켜 먹는다. 

예전에는 신문을 통해 뉴스를 보고 직접 시장에 가서 일상품을 구입했으며 식당에 가서 식사하거나 전단지의 전화번호를 이용해 음식을 배달시켰다. 이처럼 현대인은 과거와 다른 일상을 살아가는데, 가장 중요한 점은 따로 있다. 초연결 사회의 네트워크 경제에서는 수익 발생의 원리가 기존 경제 질서와 근본적으로 다르다는 것이…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[숫자를 읽는 힘/게리 스미스 지음, 이정란 옮김/지식노마드]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270531537</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270531537"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T02:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[숫자를 읽는 힘
게리 스미스 지음, 이정란 옮김 / 지식노마드 / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9791187481904
정가: 18,000원 / 판매가: 16,200원 / 마일리지: 70원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




데이터를 고문해 도출한 수십 개의 왜곡된 주장이 등장한다. 그리고 주장의 근거로 사용된 데이터와 숫자가 어떻게 우리의 편향된 뇌를 통해 객관적인 통계를 주관적인 믿음으로 왜곡시키는지 보여준다. 이를 통해 우리의 눈을 가리는 통계적 장난에 더는 속지 않고 세상을 제대로 이해할 수 있도록 돕는다. 특히 요즘같이 가짜 뉴스가 여론을 호도하고 팩트와 거짓의 경계가 모호한 때 통계 감수성을 일깨우고 진실된 주장과 거짓된 주장을 구별하는 데 유익한 지침을 제공한다.

1부 인간 심리와 속임수

1장 우리의 패턴 추구 성향을 이용한다 
문어 폴은 어떻게 우승국을 맞혔나 | 우리가 모르는 수많은 예측 | 속임수에 넘…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1일 1페이지 부자수업/이현식.최현진 지음/지식노마드]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270531213</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270531213"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T02:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1일 1페이지 부자수업
이현식.최현진 지음 / 지식노마드 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791187481911
정가: 16,000원 / 판매가: 14,400원 / 마일리지: 64원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




신한생명과 신한은행에서 VIP 고객 자산 상담을 한 저자들이 1일 1페이지로 경제와 투자의 핵심 개념과 기본 지식을 쉽고 재미있게 공부할 수 있도록 쓴 책으로, 7개의 주제 총 365개의 꼭지로 구성되어 있다. 경제를 움직이는 핵심 원리와 개념, 현대 사회를 만들어온 산업과 상품, 주식을 비롯한 금융시장과 투자에 대해서 핵심만 뽑아 하루 한 페이지씩 공부할 수 있도록 썼다.

국내도서 > 경제경영 > 재테크/투자 > 재테크/투자 일반
국내도서 > 경제경영 > 경제학/경제일반 > 경제이야기]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[한국 경제 미래 담론/이철환 지음/새빛]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270523759</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270523759"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T01:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[한국 경제 미래 담론
이철환 지음 / 새빛 / 2021년 05월 / ISBN:9791191517033
정가: 18,000원 / 판매가: 16,200원 / 마일리지: 75원
이벤트: 5월 특별 선물! 본투리드/어린왕자/둘리 티셔츠(이벤트 도서 포함, 국내서.외서 5만원 이상)




관료 출신 경제전문가로 살아온 저자 이철환 교수는 코로나19 등 우리 경제가 처한 여러 어려움을 슬기롭게 극복하고 나아가 국민들이 행복감을 느끼며 살아갈 수 있을지에 대해 고민을 하고 있다. 또 일반적으로 어렵고 딱딱한 분야로 인식되고 있는 경제 문제를 좀 편하게, 그리고 이해하기 쉬운 방식으로 접근하여 경제에 대한 관심을 제고하고자 이 책을 썼다. 그리고 이 책에서는 현재의 경제현실을 진단하고, 새로운 미래경제와 정책방향을 제시하여 독자들에게 앞으로 다가올 경제상황을 설명하고 있다.

1장 병든경제
시장경제의 후유증과 제대로 작동되지 않는 시장원리
무기력경제, 고용 없는 성장의 딜레마 
탐욕경제 이기심과 도덕적해이의 만…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Africa's own Green Revolution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/dean-yang-africa-green-revolution</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/dean-yang-africa-green-revolution"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Green Revolution of the mid-20th century left sub-Saharan Africa behind. We spoke with Dean Yang about his paper in the American Economic Journal: Applied Economics that measured the potential effects from temporary subsidies to help farmers boost crop yields.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time Will Tell: Recovering Preferences When Choices Are Noisy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713732?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/713732?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T01:47:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlos Alós-Ferrer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Money and matriculation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/news/charts/lottery-wins-college-decisions</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/news/charts/lottery-wins-college-decisions"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winning the lottery boosts the odds that a family will send a child to college, but only if they win big, according to a  paper in the American Economic Review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JPE Turnaround Times, Previous Two Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714580?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/714580?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T09:12:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Volume 129, Issue 5, Page 1666-1666, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The University of Chicago Press: Journal of Political Economy: Table of Contents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back Cover]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/715047?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/715047?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T09:11:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Volume 129, Issue 5, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The University of Chicago Press: Journal of Political Economy: Table of Contents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front Matter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/715046?af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/715046?af=R"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T09:11:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Political Economy, Volume 129, Issue 5, May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The University of Chicago Press: Journal of Political Economy: Table of Contents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[코딩마법서 파이썬 1 STONE VERSION/오일러 저자/오일러BOOKS]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270274061</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270274061"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T06:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[코딩마법서 파이썬 1 STONE VERSION
오일러 저자 / 오일러BOOKS / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9791197008412
정가: 45,000원 / 판매가: 40,500원 / 마일리지: 177원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




기초부터 심화까지 모두 6단계로 나누어지며, 이번 책은 코딩마법서 첫 번째 STONE 버전으로 코딩 입문자를 위한 개념서와 해법서로 구성되어 있다. 우선적으로 배워야 하는 것은 알고리즘을 동반한 문제해결 전략을 배워야 한다.

_이 책을 집필하며..
_이렇게 공부 하세요.
_온라인저지 오일러OJ https://euleroj.io
_유튜브 채널 오일러TV
_목차

Chapter 01. 프로그램 선택 및 설치하기
01.1 파이썬(Python)의 유래
01.2 파이썬(Python)의 특징
01.3 컴퓨터(Computer)는 2진수로 구성되어 있다. Binary number
01.4 에디터와 인터프리터 Editor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI CODING/정락현 지음/코쿤아우트]]></title>
        <id>http://www.aladin.co.kr/shop/wproduct.aspx?itemID=270255572</id>
        <link href="http://www.aladin.co.kr/rsscenter/go.aspx?rssType=2&amp;type=item&amp;itemId=270255572"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T03:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI CODING
정락현 지음 / 코쿤아우트 / 2021년 04월 / ISBN:9791196808082
정가: 30,000원 / 판매가: 27,000원 / 마일리지: 115원
이벤트: 컴퓨터/IT 분야
 3만원 이상 구매시, 손목 보호 쿠션




구글 브라우저 '크롬'의 이름도 몰랐던 저자가, 50대에 퇴직을 앞두고 독학으로 익힌 '코딩'의 모든 것을 다룬다. 가장 기본적인 개념부터 시작해 파이썬 코딩 13단계, 약 110여 개의 인공지능 과제를 해결하는 여정을 따라가며 알파고의 원리와 코딩 스킬을 학습하여 인공지능 코딩에 익숙해지도록 구성했다.  

코딩을 익히기 위해 굳이 노트북이나 PC 앞에 앉을 필요는 없다. 이 책은 '스마트폰'을 활용해 알파고 프로그래밍 언어 '파이썬(Python)'으로 구글 코랩(Colab) 사이트에서 코딩을 실습하고 구글 드라이브에 저장하는 방법으로, 언제 어디서든 코딩 활용이 가능한 방법을 제시한다. 

또한 코로나19 게놈분석, 임대주택 맵, 바이오리듬 등 실…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>알라딘 &lt;noSpam.rss@aladdin.co.kr&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>