<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/index.html</id>
    <title>anari: slimfeed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-11T02:28:23.481Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.6.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://anarinsk.github.io/rss-osmosfeed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Your First Developer Job through Intelligent, Genuine Networking]]></title>
        <id>605cf4879618b008528a77e2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/networking-for-aspiring-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T01:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's not about what you know, it's about whom you know." "70-80% of jobs are found via someone's network." Most of us have heard cliches and stats like the above. And I think most of us intuitively know that having a network of people that can help us find opportunities]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ace Your Coding Interview – Advice from a Senior Software Engineer]]></title>
        <id>60953e202cd0545b5e943a8b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-acing-your-coding-interview-advice-from-senior-software-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical interviews are one of the most stressful parts of landing a job in tech.  You don't know what questions the interviewer is going to ask. What if you have no idea how to solve the problem in front of you? What if you freeze up and look like you]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[School spending matters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/state-education-spending-recession-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/state-education-spending-recession-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recession-induced cuts to school spending had lasting ill-effects on test scores and college enrollment, especially in states where schools rely more heavily on state aid, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Economic Policy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Systems Book Recommendations – Learn How to Build and Understand ML Systems]]></title>
        <id>609558382cd0545b5e943c6f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-systems-book-recommendations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T21:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Good friends, good books, and a sleepy conscience: this is the ideal life.” ― Mark TwainI hope you’re reading this blog in your pjs looking forward to a rejuvenating and healthy weekend.  I have been working on multiple projects lately, from creating Machine Learing Engineering and Machine Learning Operations courses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recursion Might Seem Scary – But it Doesn&#x27;t Have to Be]]></title>
        <id>609551f02cd0545b5e943bc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recursion-doesnt-have-to-be-scary/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T16:59:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any concept that we don't fully understand can be scary at first. Recursion is a topic that programming students don't learn right away. But that doesn't mean it needs to be scary or cause anxiety. In fact, recursion is a concept that we can define rather simply. According to Wikipedia:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Captive shoppers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/jerusalem-city-prices-supermarkets</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/jerusalem-city-prices-supermarkets"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why do the poor pay more? A paper in the American Economic Journal: Economic Policy investigates how socioeconomic standing interacts with spatial frictions among supermarket shoppers in Jerusalem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is &quot;Lifting State Up&quot; in React?]]></title>
        <id>609409c201fc34080ef81f97</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-lifting-state-up-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T21:41:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a simple and practical example what it means to "lift state up" in React, and how it can help you build your applications. Lifting state up is a common pattern that is essential for React developers to know. It helps you avoid more complex (and often unnecessary) patterns]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Use the Chrome DevTools to Troubleshoot Websites]]></title>
        <id>609415eb2cd0545b5e943534</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-how-to-use-the-chrome-devtools-to-troubleshoot-websites/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome DevTools is a set of web developer tools built directly into the Google Chrome browser. They can be super helpful for web developers. We just published a crash course that will teach you how to use Chrome DevTools to improve your productivity as a web developer. You will learn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optional Types in Swift – How to Use and Unwrap Optionals]]></title>
        <id>60939bde01fc34080ef81a19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/optional-types-in-swift/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're coming from Java, C++, or other object-oriented languages, chances are that you've never come across optional types or "optionals". And you might be quite surprised to know that such a concept exists in Swift. Optionals are a fundamental topic that you need to thoroughly understand to code in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python and OpenCV Course –Create Computer Vision Apps in the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>609307e801fc34080ef8191e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-computer-vision-apps-in-the-cloud-with-opencv-and-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:11:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a library of programming functions mainly aimed at real-time computer vision.  We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to use OpenCV in the cloud with Python. Misbah Mohammed created this course. He has a lot of experience with machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decomposing news shocks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/oil-supply-news-opec-announcements</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/oil-supply-news-opec-announcements"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Production announcements from OPEC have a profound impact on oil prices and the US economy, even when current oil supplies don’t change, according to a paper in the American Economic Reviewg.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Async Await Tutorial – With Asynchronous JavaScript Examples]]></title>
        <id>609011fd8eb3fb07cf09a034</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-js-async-await-tutorial-with-asynchronous-javascript-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A complete guide to Node.js async await]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy a Directory in Linux – How to cp a Folder in the Command Line in Linux and Unix (MacOS)]]></title>
        <id>608f5ad48eb3fb07cf099ddb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/copy-a-directory-in-linux-how-to-cp-a-folder-in-the-command-line-in-linux-and-unix-macos/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To copy files or directories in Unix-based operating systems (Linux and MacOS), you use the cp command. The cp command is a relatively simple command, but its behavior changes slightly depending on the inputs (files vs directories) and the options you pass to it. To view the documentation or manual]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The effectiveness of HARP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/mortgage-refinances-debt-default-spending-harp</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/mortgage-refinances-debt-default-spending-harp"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Relaxing borrowing constraints on underwater homeowners was an important tool for relieving households after the Great Recession, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics. It may have made monetary policy more effective as well]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Africa's own Green Revolution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/dean-yang-africa-green-revolution</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/dean-yang-africa-green-revolution"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Green Revolution of the mid-20th century left sub-Saharan Africa behind. We spoke with Dean Yang about his paper in the American Economic Journal: Applied Economics that measured the potential effects from temporary subsidies to help farmers boost crop yields.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Money and matriculation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/news/charts/lottery-wins-college-decisions</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/news/charts/lottery-wins-college-decisions"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winning the lottery boosts the odds that a family will send a child to college, but only if they win big, according to a  paper in the American Economic Review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welfare reform and the next generation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/intergenerational-spillovers-disability-insurance-netherlands</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/intergenerational-spillovers-disability-insurance-netherlands"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A paper in the American Economic Journal: Applied Economics found that kids in the Netherlands whose parents had their disability support reduced in the 1990s were less likely to use disability insurance as adults and completed more schooling.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling in election fraud]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/afghanistan-cell-phone-election-fraud</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/afghanistan-cell-phone-election-fraud"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cell phone access empowered voters in Afghanistan to get more involved with poll monitoring and potentially deterred fraud, highlighting how communication infrastructure can help improve election oversight, according to a paper in the American Economic Journal: Applied Economics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the United States has the best research universities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/research-universities-incentives-resources-virtuous-circles-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/research-universities-incentives-resources-virtuous-circles-us"/>
        <updated>2021-04-14T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US universities lead the world in research, but their ascendancy started earlier than many people believe. We spoke with Miguel Urquiola about his paper in the Journal of Economic Perspectives that explores which schools propelled them to the top and what policymakers can learn from that history.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Smith (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The risk of research]]></title>
        <id>https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/research-development-spillover-tradeoff</id>
        <link href="https://www.aeaweb.org/research/charts/research-development-spillover-tradeoff"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firms have to balance the benefits of spending on scientific research against the costs from that science "spilling out" to rivals. A paper in the American Economic Review investigates how this tradeoff affects R&D investment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Fleisher (research.highlights@aeapubs.org)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>